虎胆龙威 3
纽约大劫案
海伦  召集炸弹处理组  特勤人员
Helen, bomb squad, special services,
州警  还有联邦调查局
state police and the FBI!
杰金森警官  你和紧急处理中心
Lieutenant Jergenson, you and Palmer, I want you to go to St. John's emergency...
到现场去防止路人留在街道上
in case we got any walk-ins from the street.
雷蒙  去找市政府工程处
Kramer, get the city engineer.
我必须有损害报告  非常重要
I got to find out a damage report. It's very important.
炸弹  谁会想炸掉百货公司?
Bonwit Teller. Who the hell would want to blow up a department store?
你见过错过鞋子大减价的女人吗?
Did you ever see a woman miss a shoe sale?
康妮  我要你开始查证名单
Connie, I want you to get started on a witness sheet.
瑞奇  你和乔要确定穿制服的
Ricky, you and Joe, you make sure the uniforms...
在现场妥善的维护秩序
got it cordoned off there.
别让电视台的人到那去
And you don't let the damn TV crews in.
文森
Benson!
-警官  你的电话  -现在不行
- Inspector, phone. - Not now.
文森  你负责交通
Benson, traffic.
3点前清理完  否则又要大塞车
You get Fifth Avenue cleared up by 3:00 or we've got the traffic jam from hell!
-瓦尔特  -什么事?
- Walter! - Yeah?
我觉得你最好接下这个电话
I think you'd better take this.
重案组  考博警官
Major Case Unit. Inspector Cobb.
单纯的赛门去找管匠索取他的派
Said Simple Simon to the pie man, going to the fair...
不听话我就敲你的脑袋
"Give me your pies or I'll cave your head in."
要了解  爆炸只是想引起注意
You see, Bonwits was just to make sure I had your attention.
请问麦克莱恩警官是否在那里?
Is there a detective named McClane there?
他在停职中
He's on suspension.
不  瓦尔特  他不能
No, Walter, he's not.
今天不能
Not today.
你是那位?
Who is this?
叫我赛门
Call me Simon.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我想要玩1场游戏
I want to play a game.
什么样的游戏?
What kind of game?
"赛门说"
"Simon Says."
赛门会告诉麦克莱恩警官去做什么
Simon's going to tell Lieutenant McClane what to do...
而麦克莱恩警官会听命行事
and Lieutenant McClane is going to do it.
若有不依将面对惩罚
Noncompliance will result in a penalty.
什么惩罚?
What penalty?
公共场所的另外1次爆炸
Another big bang in a very public place.
你要麦克莱恩警官去做什么?
What is it that you want Lieutenant McClane to do?
赛门说麦克莱恩警官要去138街
Simon says Lieutenant McClane is to go to the corner...
和阿姆斯特丹街的交汇处
of 138th Street und Amsterdam...
假如我没记错  应该是在哈林区
which is in Harlem if I'm not mistaken.
密瓦斯基  蓝柏
Kowalski! Lambert!
你们知道在那能找到麦克莱恩吗?
You know where to find McClane?
我怀疑你能在教堂里找到他
Well, I kind of doubt you're gonna find him in church.
你必须找到那块石头
Well, you better find out what rock he's under...
并且把它带回来
and kick it over.
约翰
John.
谢了
Thanks.
多给两片
Give me two more. Come on.
老天  你看起来一塌糊涂
Jesus, John, you look like shit.
我们离开办公室时还剩什么案子
Where did we leave off with that roster?
红灯区有3起杀人事件已拖了2天
Well, we got three killings in Redhook the past two nights.
派麦伦去查
Put Miner on it. And Genetti.
还有吉纳迪  他说可能会来上班
The mayor's office will call before the day's out.
长岛有14辆倾卸车失窃
Next, 14 dump trucks stolen from a yard in Staten Island.
14辆?  有人要开建筑公司?
Fourteen. Jesus. What, somebody starting a construction company?
不  是约翰的女房东要清理他的公寓
No, that was John's landlady, going to clean his apartment.
保险欺诈
Insurance fraud.
是加利福尼亚州当时的要案
That's a priority out in California.
合同承包商跟贼分了钱
The contractor splits the money with the thieves.
乔  记得吗?  新泽西几年前就发生过
We had that out in Jersey a couple of years ago, Joe. Remember?
看看凯利能怎么处理吧
See what Kelly can do with it.
昨晚乐透开什么号码?
Hey, what was the lottery number last night?
- 4667. - 4667. - 4667.
还是买警徽号码?  瑞克
You still betting your badge, Rick?
对  每周都是买6991
Yeah. 6991, every week.
6991  幸运号码
6991. Lucky number.
全纽约的警察都是买警徽号码
Half the cops in New York play their badges.
孩子还好吗?
How are the kids, John?
听说还好
I hear they're okay.
你和荷莉说过话吗?
Did you talk with Holly?
我没有
No, I didn't talk to Holly.
到了  警官
Coming up on it, Inspector.
我怕的要命
Hot in here or am I just scared to death?
去确定枪贴好了
You want to make sure the gun's secure?
没问题
Yeah, it's good.
除了荷莉以外你是第一个女的
You know, you're the first woman since Holly...
看到我做这件事
who's seen me do this.
我真荣幸
I'm honored.
她也是
Yeah, so was she.
支援会在哪儿?
So where's the backup gonna be?
我们要后撤到128街
We're gonna drop back to 128th Street.
什么?
What?
10条街以外  你们逗我玩?
Ten blocks? Are you fuckin' kiddin' me?
哥们儿  太棒了
Oh, man, that's just great.
瓦尔特  这究竟是怎么回事?
Well, hey, Walter, what is all this about, huh?
假如我不照做  那家伙说
If we don't do what this guy says,
他会在公共场所引爆另一颗炸弹
he's gonna blow up another public place.
为什么是我?  与我有什么关系
Well, why me? What does he got to do with me?
我不清楚  他说一定要你
I have no idea. He just said it had to be you.
感觉被需要真好
Huh. It's nice to be needed.
老实说  约翰
Frankly, John...
瓦尔特  别再提荷莉的事行不行?
Hey, Walter, how about you mind your fuckin' business about Holly, huh?
你和西蒙真是最好的解酒药
You and Simon are fuckin' up a perfectly good hangover.
行了
Okay.
我们15分钟后来接你
We'll be back to pick you up in 15 minutes.
不着急  我最多活个4分钟
Take your time. I expect to be dead in four.
我们走  比利
Let's go, Billy.
这回死了
Man.
叔叔
Hey, yo, Uncle!
来看看这个
Come look at this.
9点10分了  为何不在学校里?
It's ten after 9:00. Why aren't you in school?
汤尼想把这个卖给你
Tony wants to sell you this.
汤尼?
Tony?
那么没脖子被叫做坏T的家伙?
That no-neck dude they call Bad T?
他说他在垃圾堆找到这个
He says he found it in a Dumpster.
他一直偷人家东西
He keeps stealing from people,
某天他会在垃圾堆里被发现
they're gonna find him in a Dumpster.
他没有偷
No, he didn't steal it.
他说是他叔叔给他的
He says his uncle gave it to him.
把那边的报纸递给我
Mm-hmm. Hand me that newspaper over there.
别让别人利用你
Don't ever let people use you.
你提着脏物在大街走
You're running all over town with stolen property.
被抓到时  你就麻烦了
If you get caught, you get in trouble...
他只要否认就能脱身  你却得坐牢
while he gets to deny the whole thing and walk away.
你是说要我们拿回去给汤尼?
Y-You mean, you want us to take it back to Tony?
不  我拿去还给他  和他谈谈
No, I'll take it back to Tony, with a message.
-现在  你们要去那里?   -去学校
- Now, where you goin'? - School.
-为什么?   -去受教育
- Why? - To get educated.
-为什么?   -好上大学
- Why? - So we can go to college.
-它为何那么重要?   -以便得到尊敬
- And why is that important? - To get 'espect.
受尊敬  谁是坏人?
Respect. Now, who's the bad guys?
-卖毒品的人 -有枪的人
- Guys who sell drugs. - Guys who have guns.
-谁是好人?   -我们是好人
- And who are the good guys? - We're the good guys.
-谁会帮你?   -没有人
- Who's gonna help you? - Nobody.
-那么谁会帮助你?   -我们自己帮助自己
- So who's gonna help us? - We're gonna help ourselves.
-谁不会帮助我们?   -白人
- And who do we not want to help us? - White people.
没错
That's right.
快去上学吧
Now get on outta here. Go to school.
-叔叔  你最好来看看这个 -看什么?
- Uncle, you better come look at this. - What?
因为有个白人站在街上
There's a white man standing in the street.
我看到过
I seen one.
这个你肯定没见过
Not like this.
我恨黑鬼
报警
Dial 911.
叫警察快点到这来
Tell the police to get up here quick.
有人要没命了
Somebody's about to get killed.
你们上学去  听到了吗?
And get your butts to school, you hear me?
-听到了  -好
- Yeah. - All right.
早上好
Morning.
Good morning.
你今天过得好呗?  先生
You havin' a nice day, sir?
感觉不错吧?
You feelin' all right?
无意针对你个人
Not to get too personal,
但一个白人站在哈林区的中央
but a white man standing in the middle of Harlem...
身上挂着我恨黑鬼的牌子
wearin' a sign that says "I hate niggers"...
若不是有强烈的个人诉求
has either got some serious personal issues
就是不顾死活了
or not all his dogs are barkin'.
我在跟你说话呢
Hey, I'm talkin' to you!
在被那些人看见之前你有10秒钟
Now you got about ten seconds before those guys see you.
他们看见会杀了你
And when they do, they will kill you.
听懂了吗?
You understand?
那你就要有个糟糕的一天了
You are about to have a very bad day.
还用你说
Yeah, tell me about it.
先生  这是警察公务  为您的安全着想  我要求你
Sir, this is a police matter. For your own safety, I'm gonna ask you...
-站到街道那边  -这当然是警察的事  但考虑你的安全
- to step across the street. - You're damn right... It's a police matter! For your own safety...
我建议你在警察来之前躲到我店里
I suggest you hide your butt in my shop 'til the police get here.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
糟了
Aw, shit.
听我说  我是警察
Listen, I'm a cop.
-什么?  -我在执行公务
- What? - I'm on a case.
1小时前有件爆炸案
Somebody blew up Bonwit Teller's an hour ago.
-你听广播了吗?  -听了
- Did you hear about that on the news? - Yeah.
是同一个混球叫我这么做的
The same asshole who did that said I got to come to Harlem...
若我不做他就炸掉别的  懂吗?
and do this or he's gonna blow up something else. Do you understand?
破事  烂事  混蛋
Shit, shit, shit.
-听着  我有枪  -他们有10把枪
-Listen, I got a gun. - They got ten guns.
你该去街那边
If you can get across the street,
你该过街去
you should get across the street!
听着  开始装疯
Look, start acting crazy, all right?
什么?
What?
像个神经病  明白吗?
All right? Like Looney Tunes. You know, like Bellevue.
宙斯  这是你朋友?
Hey, Zeus, this a friend of yours?
他像我的朋友吗?
He look like a friend of mine?
我想这小子刚从医院偷跑出来
I think the dude just escaped from some hospital,
神经病院之类的
you know, like Bellevue.
我是
I am the...
我自己的神
voice of my own god,
我的神
and my god...
我告诉管理员我的头很痛  但她不信
And I grant that I had a bad headache, but she didn't believe me.
你们要相信  我的头真的很痛
I really do have a bad headache, though. I have a very bad headache!
我感觉象是...
And my head does not feel...
去你的
Oh, man, shut the fuck up!
这SB是谁?
Who is this fucker?
-你犯了个很严重的错误  -踢他的小屁屁
- You've made a very bad mistake. - Kick his little ass.
-哟  -大家伙儿  怎么玩?
- Boot your ass! - Yo! - Look, boy, what's the game?
-把那牌子弄掉  -打扁你脸
- Cut that shit off! - In your face, boy! - Ooh, yeah!
伙计们  伙计们
Fellas! Fellas!
这白小子恨黑鬼
Nature boy here hates niggers.
我们该怎么办?
Now what are we gonna do about that?
慢着  慢着
Yo, yo, yo, yo! Hold up, hold up, hold up!
我的胳膊
Oh, shit!
做了他
Get him!
退后!  退后
Back! Back up!
宙斯  你是怎么回事?
Hey, what you trippin' on?
-退后!  立刻退后  -你挺有种是吧?
- Back the fuck up now! - Hey, you got a whip too, boy?
-起来  -黑哥  你也是警察!
- Come on, man, get up. - Yo, black man, you must be a cop!
快点跑
Get outta here! Come on. Get outta here now!
上出租车  快上出租车
Grab the cab! Grab the goddamn cab!
-别开枪  -别让出租车走掉
- Don't shoot, huh? Don't shoot me! - Don't lose that cab!
站起来  快站起来
Get up! Come on! Get up!
退后  我不想开枪但我会的
Back up! I mean it! I don't want to, but I will!
你们晓得我会开枪的
You know I will! Come on!
快点  开车!  开车!
Come on! Drive! Drive! Drive!
快走!  快走!
Go! Go!
快带我们离开这里
Go! Get the fuck outta here!
开车  别停下来  继续开
Drive! Drive! Don't stop! Just keep drivin'!
-闯红灯  -兄弟  别开枪!
- Run the red light! Drive, goddamn it! - Don't shoot, man!
我只有这么多
That's all I got!
把你的钱收起来
Put that fuckin' money away.
-没人要打劫你  -也别杀我
- Nobody's robbin' you, asshole. - Don't kill me!
我想杀了你
I'll fuckin' kill you.
一路闯红灯  尽管开
Just run all the lights! Drive.
-听你的  老大  -痛
- You got it, boss! - Damn!
割的深吗?
That cut deep?
我怎么晓得?
How the hell would I know?
一直压着的
Just keep pressure on it.
太糟糕了
Oh, fuck!
苏斯  对吧?
Jesus, right?
我是约翰·麦克莱恩
John McClane.
我欠你份情
I owe you one.
-你当然欠我一份情  -谢谢你救
- Damn right you owe me! - Thanks for saving...
你知道他们现在会怎么砸我的店
You got any idea what those guys are doing to my shop right now?
冷静点
Chill out, Jesus.
-冷静点?  -我们会派辆车去的
- "Chill out"? What the fuck? - We'll send a car up there.
你想和我攀亲带故吗?
Are you trying to relate to me?
像个白人那样讲话
Talk like a white man.
苏斯  对不起  我
Look, Jesus, I'm sorry you got involved, all right?
你怎么一直叫我苏斯
Why do you keep calling me "Jesus"?
在你眼里我像波多黎哥人吗?
I look Puerto Rican to you?
刚才那些人叫你苏斯
Guy back there called you "Jesus," didn't he?
他们不是叫我苏斯  是宙斯
He didn't say, "Jesus." He said, "Hey, Zeus."
-我的名字叫宙斯  -宙斯
- My name is Zeus. - Zeus?
没错  宙斯  阿波罗的父亲
Yeah, Zeus! As in father of Apollo,
住在奥林帕斯  别惹我
Mount Olympus... don't-fuck-with-me
否则我用闪电劈你  我叫宙斯
-or-I'Il-shove- a-lightning-bolt-up-your-ass Zeus!
你有意见吗?
You got a problem with that?
不  我对那个没意见
No.  I don't have a problem with that.
市区  警察局
Downtown. Police plaza.
那真是太好了
Oh-ho. Oh, that's just great.
不管肤色  列出他逮过的每一个
Get a record of all his collars, recent releases...
被他注意过的也要列出来
and list of anybody else he might have looked at sideways.
需要催化剂才会让神经病有幻想
It's textbook megalomania. It's a pathological state...
他能够主宰一切
in which fantasies of control or omnipotence predominate.
他想要控制他  他的行动  思想
He wants control over him. He wants control...
甚至他的情绪  感情
over his actions, over his thoughts, even his emotions.
听起来像是你有位神秘的仰慕者
Sounds like you got a secret admirer, John.
也许他会送花来给我
Yeah, maybe he'll send me some flowers.
大家都晓得你邋遢成习
Everybody knows you like pansies.
不是那种感情  那家伙很丑陋
It's not that kind of emotion. This guy is ugly.
他的情况如何?
How is that?
他只要冲个澡就能治好
Nothing wrong with him a shower wouldn't cure.
啤酒通常是喝到肚子里的  约翰
Beer is normally taken internally, John.
请给我几颗阿斯匹灵
Just give me some aspirins, will you?
我去拿  自己按住这
Yeah, okay. Hold this here.
这是弗雷德·席勒  约翰  他是
This is Fred Schiller, John, and he's a...
是心理医师  我知道
A shrink. Yeah, I got it.
我们在对付的是个妄想狂
Yes. I was saying that we're dealing with a megalomaniacal personality...
可能还是偏执狂
with possible paranoid schizophrenia.
略过这一段直接告诉我后面的
Hey, hey, how about we just skip down to the part...
这与我有什么关系?
where you tell me what the fuck this has to do with me, huh?
我不知道  我所知道的是
I don't know. I mean, what I do know is it does have specifically to do with you.
这家伙想要打击你
This guy wants to pound on you 'til you crumble.
要你随着他的节拍起舞
He wants you to dance to his tune and then...
想让我脱掉衣服给他搞?
Put on a dress and fuck me?
我本来要说杀你
I was going to say, "kill you."
他目前愤怒异常
He's sitting on an awful lot of rage...
在压力之下他要发泄出来
and it could be manifested physically if he's stressed.
被你逮捕的人  被你激怒的人?
Somebody you arrested? Somebody you pissed off?
那名单可长了
Well, that could be one hell of a long list.
去你的  乔
Fuck you, Joe.
那种人不喜欢匿名行事
See, these people don't like to work anonymously.
他们想要你知道是谁在那样对你
They want you to know who's doing it to you.
所以赛门这个名字可能不是假名
So this name Simon is probably not an alias.
是真名或是相关的
It's probably Simon or some variation.
赛门·罗伯特·E  86年被捕
Simon, Robert E. Busted in '86.
敲诈勒索  绑架  10到15年刑期
Extortion, kidnapping. Ten to fifteen.
服刑7年后
Did seven years for good behavior...
因表现良好两个月前假释
released on a state work furlough two months ago.
查查看
Check it.
谢了  雷
Thanks, Rick.
巴伯赛门是个生意人
Bob Simons was a bankrupt businessman...
他绑架了合伙人的女儿
who kidnapped his partner's daughter.
他是想不开而不是疯子
He's a fuck-up not a psycho.
我们要找的人是疯子
The guy we're looking for is nuts.
一个很懂炸弹的疯子
A nut who knows a lot about bombs.
我们在游乐场找到这个
We found this in a playground.
专业级  很正点的东西
Professional, very cool stuff. You know, boom.
可以这样摔来摔去的吗?  查理
You think you should slam it around like that, Charlie?
尚未混合  不会炸
It's unmixed. You can't hurt it.
这玩意儿很先进  是两液型的
This stuff is cutting-edge. It's a binary liquid.
什么?
A what?
象是环氧树脂  两液型的
Like epoxy. Two liquids.
其中任何单独一种
Either one by itself...
什么也不会发生  但混合它们之后
You got nothing. But mix 'em...
理奇
Ricky.
你为何要炸掉那张椅子
Charlie, you're gonna be wearin' that chair up your ass!
查理  你在干什么?
Christ Almighty, Charlie!
像我所做的  很正点的东西
Like I said, very cool stuff.
从现在开始  凡是这类包装都要小心
Now, with a package like this, you get a warning.
炸弹得先自行装配
Now, the bomb has to arm itself.
你会看见红色液体在引爆之前
You'll see the red liquid pump into...
会泵进透明液体中
the clear before it detonates.
爆炸前有多久?
How long before?
10秒  2分钟  任何可能都有
Ten seconds. Two minutes. Could be anything.
一旦它们混合了
But once it's mixed,
你最好是在别的地方
be somewhere else.
这玩意应该很罕见
This stuff has got to be pretty rare.
我们应该查查看什么地方丢了这种东西
We ought to be able to find out if any of it's missing somewhere.
已经查到了
I already did.
利弗莫尔实验室周末时遭窃
Livermore Labs. Theft over the weekend.
足够再做另一个?  乔
Has he got enough to make another one, Joe?
约2千磅
About 2,000 pounds.
那种东西?
Of that?
引爆信号有任何可能
Well, the detonating mechanism can be anything:
无线信号  电子
Radio, electrical.
你甚至能用呼叫器
Hell, you could use a beeper and phone it in.
警官  警官  那人打来电话
Inspector! Inspector, it's him.
做炸弹的人用了阿尔贝蒂双反馈回路
He's got a double Alberti feedback loop on it.
曾经在黎巴嫩用过的恶毒的引爆手法
A nasty little trick I believe once used in Lebanon.
查理  查理!
Charlie. Charlie!
-查理  别说了  -怎么?
- Charlie, shh. - What?
开始追踪器
Want to start the trace?
赛门
Simon.
我们把他送到那去但他幸存下来
He wore the board, walked the street and survived.
我的鸽子目前好吗?
Hauptman Walter, where are my pigeons now?
鸽子?
"Pigeons"?
我曾有2只毛色鲜艳的鸽子  有天飞走了
I had two pigeons, bright and gay, fly from me the other day.
它们为什么飞走?  你没法回答  因为你不知道
Why was it they did go? You cannot tell, you do not know.
你是指麦克莱恩
You mean McClane?
不  我指的是圣诞老人
No, I mean Santa Claus.
我在这
Yeah, I'm here.
你终于出现了  你的朋友呢?
Ah, there after all. And your friend?
卡特  那边需要你
Carver! Carver! Come on. We need you in the other room.
快点  走啊
Let's go! Come on.
他们需要你  去吧
They need you. Go.
他也在这
Yeah, he's here too.
我能和他谈谈吗?
And may I speak with him?
艾米尼和艾伦现在在那?
Well, is the ebony Samaritan there now?
你对艾米尼有意见吗?
You got a problem with ebony?
没有
No, no.
我关心的是  我费了心思
My only problem is that I went to some trouble...
为麦克莱恩准备了那场游戏
preparing that game for McClane.
你干预了设计好的计划
You interfered with a well-laid plan.
你可以把那好计划塞进好屁眼里
Yeah? Well, you can stick your well-laid plan up your well-laid ass.
那不是聪明的举动
That was not smart.
这里面牵涉到人命的事
There are lives at stake here.
时间不够  警官
Not enough time, Inspector.
你最好希望他会再打来
You better hope he calls back.
他会的
He will.
瑞奇  去叫外面的人声音小1点
Ricky, you want to tell those people to shut the hell up out there!
小声一点
Hey! Keep it down here!
赛门  他不代表我们全部
Simon. He wasn't speaking for all of us.
那很不愉快  别让它再发生
That was unpleasant. Don't let it happen again.
你叫什么名字?  孩子
So, what's your name, boy?
别叫我孩子
Don't call me "boy"!
抱歉  只是想有幽默感点
I'm sorry. It was a poor attempt at humor.
我本来想让你回家去了
I was going to send you home with a chiding...
但现在看起来
but now I think perhaps...
我们查到他了
We got him!
你应该加入
you should join the game.
是在奥斯陆的公用电话
It's a pay phone in, in Oslo.
等下  是墨西哥的佛瑞斯
No, w-wait, they say it's Juarez, Mexico.
不  现在他们说墨西哥的劳瑞斯
No, wait. No, wait. N-Now they're saying it's Juarez, Mexico.
算了  澳洲?  他捣乱了整个系统
Forget it! Australia? He's scrambling up their system.
我们根本不知道他在那里
They don't know where he is.
和电话公司玩得愉快吧?
Having fun with the phone company, are we?
赛门说麦克莱恩和那位先生
Simon says McClane and the Samaritan...
要去72街与百老汇交口地铁站
will go to the subway station at 72nd and Broadway.
我15分后打去车站外公用电话
I will call you in 15 minutes on the pay phone outside the station.
不准有警察  没接电话就算失败
No police. Failure to answer will constitute noncompliance.
你懂吗?  约翰
Do you understand me, John?
我懂
Oh, yes, I understand.
我晓得你是玩小孩的游戏
I understand that you're a fuckin' whacko that likes to play kids' games.
这就是我明白的
That's what I understand.
差得远了
Hardly.
差得远?  那么你是谁?  我抓过的
"Hardly"? Well, then, who are you? Somebody I sent up?
你做了什么?  扒手  小偷
What'd you do? Shoplifting? Purse-snatching?
男扮女装?  究竟是什么?
Cross-dressing? What?
即使我连人带椅子的把你偷走
You c-c-couldn't catch me if I stole your...
你也抓不到我
ch-chair with you in it.
连人带椅子?
My ch-ch-ch-chair with me in it? Ooh!
那真的很刺激
That's very exciting.
让我问你个问题  混球
Let me ask you a question, bonehead.
你为何想要杀我?
Why are you trying to k-k-k-k-kill me?
约翰  冷静点
John, John, calm yourself.
你为何不到警察局来?
Huh? Why don't you come on down here to police plaza...
我们以男子汉的方式来解决它
and we'll figure this out like a couple of men, huh?
到这里来
So come on down here.
你是在开玩笑  假如想要杀你
If killing you was all I wanted...
-你现在早已死透了  -赛门  这位是考博警官
- You'd be dead by now. - Simon. This is Inspector Cobb.
我很感谢你重视麦克莱恩
I can appreciate your feelings for McClane.
但相信我  那个混球不值得
But, believe me, the jerk isn't worth it.
他在警局里得罪了太多人
He's stepped on so many toes in this department...
下个月的这个时候就要他去守大门
by this time next month, he's gonna be a security guard.
他的妻子也不想和他有任何瓜葛
His own wife wants nothing to do with him...
他离真正的酒鬼只有两步之遥
and he's about two steps shy of becoming a full-blown alcoholic.
一步  一步之遥
One step. One step.
听我说  你听起来像个聪明人
Now listen to me. You sound like a real smart guy.
你想要什么?
What is it that you want?
你是在说钱吗?
Are you talking about money?
随便啦
Well, whatever, whatever.
要知道麦克莱恩只不过是只臭虫
McClane is a toilet bug.
把他忘掉  从此愉快过1生
Now, what would it take just to forget him and live happily ever after?
你知道钱对我有如粪土
You know, money is shit to me.
即使把诺克斯堡的黄金全都给我
I would not give up McClane for...
我也不会放弃麦克莱恩
all the gold in your Fort Knox.
15分后在72街地铁公用电话
72nd Street subway. Pay phone. 15 minutes.
麦克莱恩和他那位朋友
McClane and the Samaritan.
若你们还有点能力就已找到皮箱
If you're competent in the least, you found the briefcase.
那你们就晓得我说的惩罚是什么
So you know what I mean by penalty.
谢谢你对我的信心  瓦尔特
I want to thank you for that vote of confidence, Walter.
我想至少可以试试
Well, I thought it was worth a try.
这家伙已经彻底疯了
This guy's a raving maniac.
就个案来说他已说得很清楚
Well, he, he, he couldn't be any clearer if you got it from a case history.
他已经给了你有关他的身份
He gave you clues to his identity.
他带德国口音  说你们的诺克斯
He spoke German, he called it "your Fort Knox"...
当麦克莱恩激怒他时  他会变口吃
and he stammered when McClane pushed him.
你认为这家伙能用钱摆平吗?
Now, you believe this guy really can't be bought?
不可能  忘了钱会让他更愤怒吗
There's no chance. And the very mention of money only enraged him further.
那是什么?
What's that?
你的警徽
It's your shield.
你又再要我当警察了?
Are you asking me to be a cop again, Walter?
瑞奇  去把他的枪找来给他
Ricky, get him his gun, all right?
你还没有回答我的问题
You didn't answer my question.
你晓得是
Joe, this time they...
嗨!
Hey!
你没回答我的问题  瓦尔特
You didn't answer my question, Walter.
有完没完?  警官
Are you done, Lieutenant?
若你想准时到72街就得出发了
Now you two better get going if you're gonna get up to 72nd Street on time.
乔  这次要给他们后援
Joe, this time they go with backup!
没问题
You got it!
这次我那里都不去
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! I'm not going anywhere.
赛门说你必须得去
Simon says you gotta go!
我才不会为了神经病而自投险地
I'm not jumping through hoops for some psycho!
那是白人与白种问题  你去处理
That's a white man with white problems. You deal with him.
当他过了110街以后再找我
Call me when he crosses 110th Street.
你为何要救我?
Hey. Why'd you save my ass?
我没有
I didn't.
我阻止白种警察在哈林区被杀
I stopped a white cop from gettin' killed in Harlem.
今天有名白种警察被杀
One white cop gets killed today,
明天就会有上千名白种警察到那里
tomorrow we got a thousand white cops...
每个都想借机开枪  懂吗?
all of 'em with itchy trigger fingers. Got it?
把他弄回来
Get him back.
查理  你在那找到那颗炸弹的?
Charlie, where'd you find that bomb?
唐人街
Chinatown.
糟糕
Shit.
-宙斯  搭档  -什么事?
- Zeus! Yo, partner! - What?
等等
Wait up!
我不是你的搭挡
Hey, hey, hey, hey, I ain't your partner.
我不是你的邻居或朋友
I ain't your neighbor, your brother or your friend.
我是你完全的陌生人
I'm your total stranger.
好  陌生人  你晓得115街
Okay, stranger. Know where that park is...
和圣·尼古拉斯街的公园在哪吗?
at 115th Street and St. Nicholas?
知道  在哈林区
Yeah, that's in Harlem.
你以为我们在那找到那颗炸弹的
Where do you think we found that bomb?
听我说  那家伙不在乎肤色
Listen, this guy doesn't care about skin color,
你在乎也没有用
even if you do.
-我在干什么?  -振作点
- What am I doing? - Cheer up.
有可能会更糟
Things could be worse.
有段时间我上夜班
I was working on a nice, fat suspension...
除了抽烟之外你无所事事
smoking cigarettes and watching Captain Kangaroo.
走吧
Come on.
谁在用电话?
Who's that on the phone?
他们到了电话那  但有麻烦
Okay, they made it to the phone, but there's a problem.
什么意思?  麻烦大吗?
Well, what do you mean? How big a problem?
-大约3百斤那么大  -别逗了
Oh, about 300 pounds. - Pass on it.
抱歉  女士  打断一下
Ma'am? Excuse me, ma'am.
警察公务需要用这个电话
We need this phone for official police business.
莫来乱
Do you mind?
-女士  我是警察  -抱歉  我这...
- Honey, I'm a cop. - I'm sorry, but l...
我需要用这个电话
I need the phone right now.
挂断电话
Get off the damn phone, lady!
这是警察公务
Police business!
从来没遇过这样的
Well, I never!
我已经习惯这种事了
I can get used to this.
我相信你在对街能找到电话
I'm sure you can find a phone across the street, ma'am.
我们把话说清楚  我才是警务
Let's get something straight. I'm the only one here on official police business.
再也别做那种事
Don't ever do that shit again.
让我把话说清楚
Let's get something else straight.
你们需要我甚于我需要你们
You need me a lot more than I need you.
若我喜欢我办事的方法
You don't like the way I do things?
好  我不干了
Fine. I quit.
好了  我需要你
All right, I need you.
好  我需要你甚于你需要我
All right, I need you more than you need me.
哈啰
Hello.
人以群分  物以类聚
Birds of a feather flock together, so do pigs and swine.
很高兴这机会是我的
Rats and mice have their chance as will I have mine.
很好  还挺押韵
Nice. It rhymes.
电话为什么占线?  你们打给谁?
Why was the phone busy? Who were you calling?
神经病专线
The Psychic Hot Line.
我建议你正经点
I'd advise you to take this more seriously.
这是公共电话  你要我怎么说
Look, it's a public phone! What do you want me to say?
你可以直说有个胖女人在用电话
You can simply say there was a fat woman on it,
花了你们一点时间才让她离开
and it took you a minute to get her off!
约翰  你旁边垃圾筒内有炸药
Now, John, there's a significant amount of explosive in the trash receptacle next to you.
想跑的话它就会立刻爆炸
Try to run and it goes up now.
没有人会跑  但这里有上百个人
Uh, nobody's gonna run, but I got a hundred people out here.
那正是我的意图
That's the point.
我得到你们的注意了没?
Now, do I have your attention?
我当时要去圣·艾夫斯
As I was going to St. Ives,
遇到1个男的有7位太太
I met a man with seven wives.
每位太太有7个袋子
Every wife had seven sacks,
每个袋子有7只猫
every sack had seven cats,
每头猫生了7只小猫
every cat had seven kittens.
小猫  猫  袋子  太太
Kittens, cats, sacks and wives.
有几个人要去圣奈尔?
How many were going to St. Ives?
我的电话号码是555
My phone number is 555...
不  我没完全听清楚  再说一次
No, no, no, wait! I didn't get all that! Say it again!
-不可能  我的电话是555  -但我没听清
- Not a chance. My phone number is 555... - But I didn't...
加上答案的数字  三十秒内打电话给我  否则就死
and the answer. Call me in 30 seconds or die.
7个人有7个太太
All right, seven guys with seven wives is...
闭嘴  麦克莱恩  这方面我在行
Shut up, McClane. I'm good at this.
7个人有7个太太
Seven guys and seven wives...
闭嘴  麦克莱恩
Shut the fuck up, McClane!
他说7位太太各有7个袋子
He said seven wives with seven sacks.
7乘7是49  告诉我剩下的
Seven times seven is 49. Now tell me the rest.
7个袋子
Uh, a sack with s-seven, seven, seven...
-你有在听吗?  -听着呢
- Weren't you listening? - Yeah, I was listening!
-我什么也没听清  -你有什么问题?
- I didn't hear every fuckin' thing! - What the fuck is wrong with you?
我因宿醉而头痛的厉害是其1
Well, l... Besides having a bad fuckin' hangover, for one thing!
好吧  49再乘每个袋子7只猫
All right, all right, all right! Seven wives times seven, 49.
7乘49是343  对吧?
With seven cats... Seven times 49 is 343, right?
-你在问我还是在告诉我  -是你告诉我的
- What, are you asking me or telling me? - I'm telling you.
是我说的  7乘343是
343 times seven is... One, zero, 24.
2401  你算出来也一样吧?
2,401. That's what you got, right?
那就拨5552401
- That's it. Dial. 555-2401. - 555-2401.
-不  等下  是脑筋急转弯  -怎么了?  什么?
- No, wait, wait! It's a trick! - What? What? - It's a trick.
此话怎讲?
What do you mean?
我忘了那个男人
I forgot about the man.
什么男人?  去他的  还有10秒
What man? Fuck the man! We got ten seconds here!
他说有几个人要去圣·艾夫斯  对吧
He said how many were going to St. Ives, right?
遇到1个男的有7位太太
The riddle begins, "As I was going to St. Ives, I met a man with seven wives."
那个人和他的太太那都不去
The guy and his wives aren't going anywhere.
那他们要去那?
What are they doing?
坐在大路旁等着看月亮
Sittin' in the fuckin' road, waitin' on the moon!
我怎么会知道?
How the hell should I know, McClane!
那谁要去圣奈尔?
Well, who was going to St. Ives then?
那个人  只有那个人
The guy. Just the guy.
就1个人?
Just one guy?
答案是1
The answer's one.
就1个人  那怎么拨1?
Just one guy. How do you dial "one"?
555-0001!
0001.
只有1个人去
Just one guy's goin'.
哈啰  约翰
Hello, John.
小事一桩  下次出个难点的吧
Yeah, a piece of cake. Give us something harder next time.
但是你们慢了10秒
But you're ten seconds late.
不  答案是1
No, no! The answer is one!
垃圾筒里有炸弹  大家都趴下
There's a bomb in the trash can! Everybody get down!
大家快趴下
Get down! There's a bomb in the trash can!
有炸弹!
There's a bomb!
所有人都趴下  有炸弹!
Everybody get down! There's a bomb!
趴下  有炸弹!
Get down! There's a bomb!
-街头表演新艺术  -真的?
- Welcome to New York. - Really.
给你  拿着吧  我们走
Here. You can have it. Come on. Come on. Let's go.
炸弹
A bomb.
我没有说"赛门说"
I didn't say, "Simon says."
现在9点50了  约翰
It's 9:50, John.
第3号地铁现在抵达了
The Number Three train is arriving now.
我在那列火车上留了点东西
I left something provocative on that train, John.
赛门说在10点20分之前
Simon says get to the pay phone next to the news kiosk...
-到新密尔瓦基街和华尔街地铁站  -半小时
- in Wall Street Station by 10:20... - Half hour.
去接公用电话否则3号列车升天
Or the Number Three train and its passengers vaporize.
除了民用交通工具外
Use any means of travel other than civilian,
使用别的交通工具我就炸火车
I blow the train.
想疏散乘客我就炸火车
Attempt to evacuate the subway, I blow the train.
我30分钟后打给你们  要到哦!
I call you in 30 minutes. Be there.
完了
We're fucked.
在纽约的交通状况下30分内过90条街
90 blocks in 30 minutes in New York traffic?
有可能要两倍的时间
It could be double that.
我们甚至连车都没
We don't even have a car.
先生  我是警察
Hey! Hey! Sir! Sir! I'm a cop. I'm a cop.
因公务需要征用你的车
I am requisitioning this car for official police business!
搞什么吗?
What the fuck are you doing?
-非常感谢  -你干什么?  我的出租车
- Thank you very much. - What the fuck are you doing? My cab!
上车
Get in! Get in!
不错  我以前开过计程车
Pretty slick. Listen, I used to drive a cab.
去公园南边最快的路是...
The fastest way south is...
你在干什么?
What the fuck are you doing?
你说什么?
What were you saying?
我说我以前开过计程车
I was saying, I used to drive a cab...
第9大道是去公园南边最快的路
and Ninth Avenue is the fastest way south.
但我们似乎在向东走
But we seem to be going east.
你在干嘛?  麦克莱恩  我说过第9大道
Where the hell are you going, McClane? I told you Ninth Avenue...
是去公园南边最快的路
is the quickest way south!
别吼了  我知道我在干什么
Stop with the goddamn yelling! I know what I'm doing!
连上帝都不知道你在干什么
Not even God knows what you're doing!
他们向东自72街往公园走
They're headed east on 72nd towards the park.
华尔街在南边
But Wall Street is south!
别再对我吼  我头痛的要命
Man, stop yelling at me! I got a bad headache.
向南走最快的方法不是第9大道
And the best way south is not Ninth Avenue.
而是穿越公园
It's through the park.
老天
Oh, dear.
我告诉过你公园路总是堵车
I told you the Park Drive was always jammed.
我没说走公园路
I didn't say Park Drive.
我说的是穿越公园
I said, "through the park."
我们追丢了  他们正往南走
Shit! We lost them. They're in the park, headed south.
让开
Get outta here!
疯子
Crazy prick!
我发现他们了  康妮  在公园内
I got him, Connie. He's taking the scenic route.
-让开  -老兄你真行!
- Outta the way! - Oh, man.
看路  让开
Look out! Get outta there!
小心!  小心!
Watch it! Watch it! Watch it! Watch it! Watch it! Watch out!
你是在瞄准那些人吗?
Are you aiming for these people?
不是
No!
也许是在心里
Maybe that mime.
有树!  当心树!
Tree! Tree! Tree! Haul!
这里是怎么回事?
What's going on here?
小心!
Look out! Whoa!
树!  树!
Tree! Tree!
坐稳了
Just hang on.
石板!  石头!
Broads! Rock, rock!
嗨  当心这里
Hey, look out down there!
-麦克莱恩!  -干嘛?
- McClane? McClane? - What?
麦克莱恩
McClane!
让开
Outta the way.
天主徒是怎么划的?
How do Catholics do that thing?
先往下再向右再向左
North, south, west, east.
还有多少时间
How much time?
27分钟
Twenty-seven minutes.
帅!  72街到百老汇才3分钟
Ha! 72nd and Broadway to Central Park South in three minutes!
这一定是最快记录
That's gotta be a fuckin' record!
让路
Come on! Get up!
现在怎么办?
Yeah. Now what?
我们需要1辆救火车
Yeah, we need a fire truck.
什么?
What?
以便跟随
To follow.
纽约警局的约翰·麦克莱恩警官
Lieutenant John McClane, NYPD...
警徽号码7479  从民用频道呼叫
access number 7479, calling from a civilian transmitter.
要你们立刻派救护车来
Get me an emergency dispatcher right away!
好  稍候下
Dispatch. Fire.
有两位警员在14街第9大道口
I got two officers down at the corner of 14th Street and Ninth Avenue!
负伤倒地  急需救护车
Need an ambulance! Over!
他们会送往河边医院
Most of the calls on the west side go to Roosevelt Hospital.
距我们要去的地方只有两条街远
That's two blocks from here.
开慢点  麦克莱恩
Slow the fuck down, McClane!
和美式足球一样  对吧?
Kind of like football, isn't it?
什么?
What?
前面有人替你开路你直奔终点
Get yourself a blocker and head for the end zone.
你要去华尔街就得一直跟着它
If you'd said Wall Street, we could have followed him all the way.
错了  第14街是另外1家医院
Wrong. South of 14th Street's a different hospital.
坐稳了  要分开来了
Saint Luke's. Hang on.
时间
Time?
剩下18分钟了  还有18分钟的路
10:02. We're halfway there with 18 minutes to go.
去他的  坐稳了
Fuck this. Hang on.
坐稳  离开那儿
Hang on. Hang on! Hang on! Get outta there!
方向盘给你了
- Slide over and take the wheel!
你要去那?
Where you goin'?
我要先上那列火车去找
We should be ahead of that train, right?
你不能
No, you're not gonna...
-上那列火车  -我要上那列火车
- get on that train! - I'm gonna get on that train!
你10点20前要赶到那公用电话
You gotta get to that pay phone by 10:20.
你要干什么?
What are you gonna do?
我要去找那个炸弹
I'm gonna get that bomb!
听我说  你失败了有我垫底
Listen, you fail, I cover your ass.
我失败了还有你
I fail, you cover my ass.
若我们俩都失败了呢?
And if we both fail?
那就玩完了
Then we're both fucked.
快走  10点20前到那公用电话
Go, now! Drive! Get to that phone booth by 10:20! Go!
真是我的幸运日
My lucky fuckin' day.
借过  让一下
Look out! Get outta the way!
借过  借过
Look out! Look out!
当心  让开
Look out! Get outta the way!
这是个坏主意
This is a bad idea!
借过  借过
Excuse me! Excuse me!
请让路
Just get outta the way, please.
华尔街112号
112 Wall Street.
等下
Wait,
这不是计程车  你不清楚状况
this isn't a taxi. You don't understand.
你的空车灯亮着
Your light's on.
我不想麻烦  华尔街112号
I'll make it simple. 112 Wall Street,
否则我就让你吊销牌照
or I'll have your medallion suspended.
怎么  你不喜欢白人?
What? You don't like white people?
华尔街112号  没问题
112 Wall Street. You got it.
把脚抬起来  别碍事
Move your legs here. Get your legs outta the way!
抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
慌什么
Hey! Excuse me.
真扯
Shit!
借过
Excuse me. Watch out.
先生  借过
Excuse me, sir. Pardon me, please. Excuse...
请让开
Will you step outta here for a minute?
什么?
What?
我是警察  请让下
I'm a cop. Step outta here for a minute, please.
借过  请让路
Excuse me, please! Can I get through here, please?
借过
Excuse me!
Excuse me, please. It's important.
打扰  先生  我在等电话
Excuse me, sir, but I'm expecting a call.
我需要那个电话
I need that phone.
你怎么不用另外那个?
Why don't you use the other phone?
先生  拜托  我需要那具电话
Sir, please. I need to use that phone.
听着  兄弟  是我先到的
Hey, listen, bro, I was here first.
兄弟
"Bro"?
给我离开电话
Get away from the goddamn phone!
举起手来
Get your hands up!
我必须接这个电话
I have to answer that phone.
闭嘴  把手举起来
Just shut up and get 'em in the air!
小心  抱歉  借过  小心
Watch it! Excuse me! Pardon me! Watch it. Watch your back. Watch it.
各位  我是纽约市警察
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm a New York police officer.
我要你们冷静的去火车另一边
I'm gonna ask you to calmly and quietly start moving towards the other end of the car.
现在就走
Go now, please. Go now. Fuck!
快走  小心
Go! Hurry! Watch out!
小心  小心  快走
Watch. Watch it. Go!
我必须接这个电话
I have to answer that phone.
把手举高
Get 'em up!
听着  你若要开枪  尽管开
Look, if you have to shoot me then you go ahead and you shoot me!
但我必须接这个电话  行吗?
But I have to answer this phone! All right?
我在这里
I'm here.
麦克莱恩呢?
And McClane?
他在路上
He's on his way.
他身体情况不太好
Uh, you know, he's a little slow. He's kind of out of shape.
我要求的是你们两个
The rules applied to both of you.
恐怕这与我的要求不符  再见
I'm afraid this is noncompliance. Good-bye.
信任我  各位
Trust me, guys.
趴下来
Duck.
快离开那  趴下
Hey, get outta there! Get outta there! Duck, asshole!
天啊  上帝呀!
Oh, my god, Jake! Oh, my god!
麦克莱恩?
McClane?
什么状况
What?
可以看到地铁
You can see right down into the subway.
来了几辆消防车
How many fire trucks you count?
安静  安静
You guys, you guys.
我由这上面看的不是很清楚
How can you see from up there?
到下面去
Damn. Get in there.
警员  叫那些人退后  行吗?
Officer, tell those people to get the hell back, will you?
一大堆人有瘀青  几个人挫伤
We got a shitload of cuts and bruises, a couple concussions...
几位老年人心律器停了
some old guy's pacemaker stopped...
有位孕妇羊水破了 就是这样
and a pregnant girl's water broke, and that's all.
你的情况如何?  约翰
How you doin', John?
还好
Still can't hear too good.
你还活着是个奇迹
Well, it's a miracle you're still alive.
问题就出在那了  乔
Yeah, that's the problem, Joe.
什么?
What?
奇迹的部份
The miracle part.
我们能准时到这的机会有多少?
What are the odds of us making it down here on time?
零
Hmm. Zip.
那颗炸弹无论如何都会爆炸
That bomb was gonna go off no matter what.
他想要它在这里爆炸
He wanted it to go off right down here.
谢谢你帮我起来  大卫
Take this off me, Dave.
这地方为何那么特别?
Well, what's so special about this place?
我不知道  事情拼凑不起来
I don't know. Something just doesn't add up.
麦克莱恩警官?
Lieutenant McClane?
他们要找你和卡特先生
They're asking for you and a Mr. Carver.
在那?
Where?
约翰
John.
约翰  这位是安迪克罗斯
John, this is Andy Cross...
联邦调查局的
with the FBI.
这位是查尔斯先生  他是
This is Bill Jarvis. He's, uh...
我是另一个单位的
I'm, uh, with another agency.
见到你太好了
It's good to meet you.
这是麦克莱恩警官和卡特先生
This is Lieutenant McClane. This is Mr. Carver.
我们先要问几个问题
Uh, we got a couple questions first.
认识这个人吗?
You recognize this guy?
不认识
No.
这个呢?
How about this one?
你呢?
How about you?
-你认得出电话上的声音吗?  -没
- Did you recognize the voice on the phone? - No.
是否注意到有车子在跟踪你?
Have you, uh, noticed any cars following you around?
没有
No.
有人跟踪你吗?  任何方式的监视?
Anybody following you at all? Any kind of surveillance?
电话  屋子  任何不寻常的事?
Telephone? House? Anything unusual at all?
你既然提到了
Well, now that you mention it...
我的脚趾间烧痛
I have experienced a, you know, like a burning sensation between my toes.
我以为是香港脚之类的
I thought it was just some athlete's foot or something. I don't know.
你在虚应委蛇
We read your jacket, Lieutenant.
他们说你会合作
We were told you would be cooperative.
合作什么?
Cooperate with what?
-等下  -你想让我合作?  -他会
- Hey, now, wait a minute. - You want me to cooperate? - He will be.
我们在这浪费时间
We're just wasting time here in this goddamn van.
你们想分享情报
You want to share information,
先回馈一些如何
how about sending a little our way as well?
-我们想先听听他知道什么?  -这算什么
- Look, we want to hear what he knows first. - What the hell?
-你们让我们看了照片  -听着
- You give us pictures, and then... - Look,
我们想知道他知道些什么
we want to hear what he knows first.
我们知道的和你们一样  行吗?
Hey, I know as much as you know, all right?
某男正在外面安置炸弹
There's a guy out there settin' off bombs.
他自称叫赛门  说话带德国口音
He calls himself Simon. He speaks with a German accent.
不知为什么他十分生我的气
And, for some reason, he's very angry with me.
也许你们能告诉我是为什么
Now maybe you can tell me why, fellas, huh?
第一个人叫法瑞斯·塔戈
The first man there is Matthias Targo:
前匈牙利陆军  爆破专家
Was Hungarian Army, explosives expert.
我们相信现在是为乌克兰人工作
Now we believe he's working for the Iranians.
工作?
"Working"?
自主的恐怖份子  受雇于合约
Freelance terrorism, by contract.
那个女的是谁?
Who's the girl?
同居人
Targo's other half.
谣传在他们床单下摆了炸弹
Rumor is the Israelis slipped a bomb in between their sheets.
那天他不在家  也许炸死了她
Uh, he wasn't at home, but they think maybe they got her.
第2个人是前东德上校保全军官
Second man was an obscure colonel in the East German Army.
负责渗透部队  像坦克大决战中
He ran an infiltration unit;
纳粹德军所做的
the kind of thing the Nazis did at the Battle of the Bulge.
派说英文的部队
English-speaking troops...
我看过那部电影
Yeah, yeah, l-I saw the movie.
医药记录显示他饱受头痛之苦
All we know of him is GDR medical records show he suffers from migraines.
他的名字叫彼得·克里格
His name is Peter Krieg.
那是份极好的报告  各位
Well, that is an exceptional report, fellas.
现在你们要告诉我与我何干吗?
Now do you want to tell me what the hell this has to do with me?
鲁勃这个姓对你有意义吗?  警官
The name Gruber mean anything to you, Lieutenant?
有印象
It rings a bell, yeah.
-洛杉矶  -什么
- L.A. - What?
在洛杉矶大楼的那一次
That thing in the building in L.A.
彼得克里格原名是赛门·彼得·鲁勃
Peter Krieg was born Simon Peter Gruber.
他是汉斯·鲁勃的哥哥
He's Hans Gruber's brother.
-毁了  -是的  洛城的那件事
- Shit. - Yeah, it's that thing in L.A.
我们觉得他会尽一切置你于死地
We figure he's got you fitted up for a toe tag and he's gonna do anything to get it tied.
警官  是他
Inspector! Inspector, it's him.
别让他知道我们在这
Don't let him know we're here.
赛门
Simon.
不晓得车里联邦调查局的人是谁
Inspector. Now, who from the FBI is in the van, I wonder?
想想看  一定有克罗斯
Let's see, almost certainly Cross.
说吧  安德鲁  说哈啰啊
Come on, Andrew, say hello.
哈啰
Hello.
我知道你从不单枪匹马
And I know you never run alone.
所以打个招呼吧  比尔
So say hello, Bill.
还是咬眼镜来消除紧张?
Still trying to butch up by chewing on your glasses, huh?
这位先生是很斯文的
This, gentlemen, as they say, is where the plot thickens.
我在纽约的1446所学校中
I have put 2,400 pounds of explosive in one of...
放了一个2千4百磅的炸弹
the 1,446 schools in greater New York.
定时器设定在下午3点爆炸
It is fitted with a timer set to explode at exactly 3:00 p.m.
谢谢  你们的沉默表示已了解了
Thank you. Your silence says I'm understood.
你说是2千4百磅?
Did you say 2,400 pounds?
是的  请别再打岔
Yes, but please don't interrupt again!
赛门说你们若要疏散学校
Simon says if you attempt to evacuate schools...
那么炸弹会经无线电引爆
the bomb will be detonated by radio.
各位  会有人在监视的
And, gentlemen, someone will be watching.
下午3点会有一所学校消失
Repeat: One school will be dismissed at 3:00 p.m., permanently,
除非
unless...
除非什么?
Unless what?
除非约翰·麦克莱恩和他的新朋友
Unless John McClane and his new best friend...
能完成我为他们所设定的目标
complete the tasks I set them.
约翰  你在听吗?
John, are you listening?
听着呢
Yeah.
在汤金广场后面有座公用电话
The pay phone beyond Hope Thompkins Square Park.
20分钟  用走的  不必赶
Twenty minutes. Go by foot. No rush.
若你真的聪明你能用军用密码
If you're really clever, you'll learn the location of the bomb...
找到那颗炸弹
and the code to disarm it.
另外  我们买到便宜的引爆器
Oh, and by the way, gentlemen, we got something of a bargain on radio detonators.
问题是警用及FBI频率会引爆
The only problem is, the darn things seem to respond to police and FBI frequencies...
所以假如我是你们就不用无线电
so if I were you, I'd keep off your radios.
赛门  等下
Simon, wait.
2千4百磅那液体炸弹  老天
2,400 pounds of that liquid stuff. My God!
替我接局长
Get me the commissioner.
他在开记者招待会  半小时会到
He's doing a press conference. He's supposed to be here in half an hour.
好吧  瑞奇  集合现场资深警员
All right, Ricky, get every senior officer on the site. Get 'em here right away.
别跟我来那套管辖权的胡扯
You're not gonna give me any jurisdictional nonsense on this?
我两个孩子在64街的学校里
I got two kids in the school on 64th Street.
有什么地方我能帮得上忙
What can I do to help you?
你有多少人?
How many men have you got?
75  但紧急求援的话
Seventy-five, but if I push the panic button,
能从华府调5百人来
I can get 500 from Washington.
什么时候到?
When?
2点半到3点之间
2:30, 3:00.
从此刻开始
Between now and then?
我们得独自做这件事  我们走
We're gonna have to do this all by ourselves. Let's go.
汤金广场在两英里外  你们得走了
Now, Thompkins Square Park is more than two miles away, so you guys better get running.
别用无线电  带着我的电话
No radios. You take my telephone.
有任何事利用报案中心交换机
You get anything, you call me through the switchboard.
祝好运
Good luck.
谢谢  找到那颗炸弹
Thanks. Find that bomb.
瑞奇  他们在那?
Ricky, where are they?
在这边
Right over here.
最资深的是艾伦队长
Senior man present is Chief Allen.
那个单位的队长?
Chief of what?
交通
Transit.
好  谢谢  瑞奇
Okay, thanks, Ricky.
各位  我们有个决定要下
Gentlemen, we have a decision to make.
造成这件事的人说他另外安置了
Chief Allen, the man who has done this has told us...
1个很大的炸弹在纽约的学校里
that he has planted another very large bomb in a school here in the New York area.
他说我们不能疏散
And he has told us that we cannot evacuate.
但他没说我们不能搜索
But he has not said that we cannot search.
我建议我们动员每1个人
Now, I recommend we get everybody,
而且我指的是每1个人
and I mean everybody...
不论是警察  交通  消防
I'm talking about police, transit, sanitation, fire,
甚至图书馆的人
even the goddamn librarians...
而我是指即刻起我们开始搜索
and we start searching schools, and I mean right now.
我说的是市内的数千栋建筑物
I'm talking about a thousand buildings within the city limits.
我们只有3小时15分去做
And we have three hours and 15 minutes to do it in.
我们要设法尽量不让媒体知道
Now, I'd like to keep the media out of this as long as possible...
因为他们一旦涉及就会造成恐慌
because if they get in, we've got a panic.
我们大家同意吗?
Are we in agreement?
好了  大伙们  我们走
All right, come on, guys! Let's go!
立即出发  立即出发
Let's move it out! Let's move it out!
不要用无线电通讯
No radio contact! No radio contact!
他们相信了
They bought it.
可以开始了
You can begin.
筹备  安排
Hook, line...
完全成功
and sinker.
-好了  出发!  -我们走!
- All right now, men, let's go! Let's go! - Let's go, men!
出发  动起来!  下一队  快点  快点!
Let's go! Move it! Next team! Come on! Come on!
-等下  -默里?  默里  是我
- Hey, hold on! - Murray? Murray, it's me!
特利警官
Sergeant Turley! Sergeant Turley!
过去的5分钟里线路爆满
In the last five minutes, the volume of calls in here has tripled.
怎么回事?
What the hell is goin' on?
停下  让我解释下
Stop! Let me explain.
今天剩下的时间里
For the rest of the day,
我们要负责处理局里的通讯
we're supposed to handle the department's communications.
此话怎讲
What do you mean, "handle"?
他们关闭了无线电通讯
They're shutting down the police band.
所有的通讯都要通过有线电话交换机
All calls will be coming through this switchboard.
唐纳德·特朗普: 人称"地产之王"  有"财富教父"的称号
那我就要嫁给唐纳德·特朗普了
And I'm gonna marry Donald Trump.
巴伯  怎么回事?
Walsh, what's going on?
为何大家都撤离这里了?
Why'd everybody tear out of here?
潘蜜拉  看看你的表  要换班了
Come on, Pamela, look at your watch. It's comin' up on shift change.
局长担心加班费的事
The bean counters are worried about overtime...
所以我们让大家回局里打卡下班
so we sent everybody back to the precinct to punch out.
下一班随时会到
The next shift is gonna be here in a minute.
你们是满口胡说八道
You are so full of shit, Walsh!
谢谢
Thank you.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell...
警官  巴伯塔克  工程处的
Detective. Bob Thompson, City Engineer's Office.
我们要去处理损害的部份
We'd like to get an idea of the damage.
你们来的可真快
Man, you guys really got here fast.
这里是华尔街  有许多钱
Well, it's Wall Street, sir. Lot of money here.
有许多意见很多的人
Lot of opinion makers...
市长不想得罪他们  你知道吧
the mayor doesn't want to piss off, you know?
就是这里了?
This is it?
我的老天
Holy Toledo!
有人玩得很愉快
Somebody had fun.
若你能替我的同事带路我很感谢
I'd appreciate it if you'd show my associates the way down.
没问题
Yeah, yeah, sure.
吉米  有手电筒吗?
Jimmy! You got the flashlight?
墨菲你也来
Murphy! Come on! You too!
里克·沃尔什
Rick Walsh.
约翰·科克伦
John Cochran.
走吧  各位  咱们下去
Come on, gentlemen. Let's go.
你们可能也处理世贸中心案
You were probably at the World Trades.
你们晓得那是什么情况
You know what that mess was.
请通知李先生说范登先生来了
Please inform Mr. Little that Mr. Vanderfloog is here.
范登先生
Mr. Vanderfloog?
有位范登先生找李先生
There's a Mr. Vanderfloog for Mr. Little.
往下20米
Go down 20 meters! Come on!
下面的蒸汽不少
Lot of steam down here.
炸断不少蒸汽馆  像3温暖一样
Yeah, yeah, we snapped a couple of the steam pipes. It's like a sauna.
我们叫地铁的人关闭第3通道
We got the subway guys to shut down the third rail.
用后备电源
Some emergency lights?
是  用后备电源  所以有电
Yeah, emergency lights, and there's still some light...
别开枪
No shooting!
说英文
Speak English!
我不认为奥托会说英文  对吧?
Otto doesn't speak English, do you, Otto?
我们是去那找来的这个人?
Where the hell did we get this guy?
那是塔戈的人
He's one of Targo's thugs.
一直往前开
Come on, come on. Pull all the way up.
洛城是什么事?  你很有名?
So what was up with this L.A. Thing? You famous or something?
大概有名了5分钟
Yeah, for about five minutes.
别告诉我  A片大王?
Don't tell me. Rodney King, right?
去你的
Fuck you.
-你知道我们说的那位赛门吗?  -嗯
- You know this guy Simon we're talking to? - Yeah.
我在洛城将他弟弟从32楼扔下去
I threw his little brother off the 32nd floor of Nakatomi Towers out in L.A.
我想他对那件事有点生气
I guess he's a little pissed off about it.
等下  你是在告诉我
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me...
因某白人警察把某白人混球弟弟
I'm in this shit 'cause some white cop threw...
自屋顶扔下来而让我在这受罪?
some white asshole's brother off a roof?
范登先生  企业关系部  我姓李
Mr. Vanderfloog? Felix Little, Corporate Relations.
抱歉让你久等
Sorry you had to wait, but apparently...
但因地铁爆炸
there was an explosion in the subway.
触发了我们的警铃
It's played hell with our alarms, I'm afraid.
我相信没出任何问题
I trust there's nothing wrong?
托老天的福
Oh, no. Good lord, no.
一切安全无恙
Safe and secure.
你在考虑货币兑换
Now you were concerned about a currency exchange.
以一般事务而言我们并非一般商行
Uh, we are not a commercial bank in the normal sense.
我们主要是政府的中央银行
We're, we're primarily, uh... governments, central banks, that sort of thing.
财政部是主要客户
Apart from the depository, of course.
当然
Of course.
你是从事花卉生意  范登先生
And you are in the flower business, Mr. Vanderfloog?
退  退  别停
Back! Back! Come on!
下去
Come on!
不  范登先生  那是金库的电梯
Oh, no, Mr. Vanderfloog, that's the vault elevator.
抱歉
I'm sorry, it's against...
我们的警铃针对声音与尺寸
Our alarms are sonic and seismic...
因为爆炸造成反应不太好
two things, which, I'm afraid, do not react well to explosions.
地铁系统和我们有某部份冲突
You know, this, this subway business has knocked all our systems into a cocked hat.
事实上我们必须拔掉它的插头
In fact, we've had to give up and pull the plug on the whole thing.
楼下现在只有少数几个人
The repair people are downstairs now.
老天
Good lord!
是的
Yes, yes.
老天不允许  若有任何人知道
Heavens to Betsy! If anyone knew!
我以为这是货币兑换
But I thought this was a currency exchange.
我想我们还是直接提款
Oh, I think we go straight to the withdrawal.
睡吧
Go to sleep.
队长  你下来看看
Hey, Captain, you want to come down here...
有点不对劲
and take a look at this? Something's going on.
你认为如何?  贾斯  能修好吗?
What do you think, guys? Will you be able to fix that?
只要再几分钟
Just a minute now.
好了  我马上回来
Okay, I'll be right back.
趴下
Down!
退后
Stay back!
快点啊!  快点
Come on! Come on! Shit.
服务台
Ah, front desk.
我报警
Yes, call the police!
快点来  这儿遭到攻击了
Get your ass down here right now! I'm under attack!
放轻松点  也许你能活过此事
Hey, just relax, mate. Maybe you'll live through this.
我想他已经死了  亲爱的
I think he's dead, my dear.
副官  看看办公室里的人
Lieutenant, see to the office workers.
已经解决了
It's being done, Herr.
-是这里吗  -这里安全
- Is it square? - Perimeter is secure.
诺克斯堡: 位于肯塔基州路易维尔的美国国库黄金存放处
我的神啊  这简直是诺克斯堡
1千4百亿美金
140 billion dollars!
是肯塔基州的10倍
Ten times what's in Kentucky!
福特·诺克斯
Fort Knox!
那是给观光客看的地方
Ha! It's for tourists!
麦克莱恩
Yeah? McClane!
约翰  你体力不行了
John, you out of shape?
你差点没赶到
You barely made it.
是  差一点没赶到
Yeah, well, we all barely make it.
你要我们做什么?
What do you want us to do?
什么是4只脚随时预备旅行?
What has four legs and is always ready to travel?
什么?
Huh? What?
他说什么?
What'd he say?
什么东西有4只脚  随时预备旅行?
What has four legs and is always ready to travel?
搞什么?  你难道没有孩子?
What's the matter with you? Don't you have kids?
那是个大象的笑话
That's an elephant joke.
那个就是炸弹了?
Whoa. That a bomb?
是的  你过去拿吧
Yeah, go... just go ahead and grab it.
你是警察
Well, you're the cop.
赛门说在这件事上你要帮忙
Simon said you're supposed to be helping with this.
我在帮忙
I'm helpin'.
什么时候才要帮忙?
Well, when you gonna start helpin'?
在你拿到炸弹之后
After you get the bomb.
小心
Careful.
我小心着呢
I'm being careful.
别打开它
Don't open it!
什么?
What?
我必须打开它
I gotta open it.
不会有事的
Everything's gonna be all right.
我是炸弹  你刚启动了我
-完了  -完了  我叫你别打开它
- Shit! - Shit! I told you not to open it!
我相信你已经看到了信息
I trust you see the message.
炸弹装了距离感应电路  不要试图逃跑
It has a proximity circuit, so, please, don't run.
我们收到了  不会跑
Yeah, I got it. We're not gonna run.
如何停止爆炸?
How do we turn this thing off?
喷泉那有两个桶子
On the fountain there should be two jugs.
看到了吗?
Do you see them?
1个3加仑  1个5加仑
A five-gallon and a three-gallon.
往其中之一灌4加仑水
Fill one of the jugs with exactly four gallons of water...
然后放在量器上
and place it on the scale,
计时器就会停止
and the timer will stop.
重量必须精确  太多太少都会引爆
You must be precise. One ounce more or less will result in detonation.
假如5分钟后你们还活着
If you're still alive in five minutes, we'll speak again.
等下
Wait! Wait a second!
我没听懂  你听懂了吗?
I don't get it. Do you get it?
不懂
No.
去拿桶子
Get the jugs.
显然我们不能用3加仑桶去装
Obviously, we can't fill the three-gallon jug with four gallons of water, right?
很显然
Obviously.
我晓得了  这么办
All right, I know. Here we go.
我们把3加仑桶装满  对吧?
We fill the three-gallon jug exactly to the top, right?
再把3加仑桶倒入5加仑桶
Okay, now, we pour that three gallons into the five-gallon jug...
那5加仑桶就正好有3加仑
giving us exactly three gallons in the five-gallon jug, right?
-没错  -然后呢?
- Right. - Okay. - Then what? - Now, we take...
然后在3加仑桶内装3分之1
the three-gallon jug, we fill that a third of the way up...
不行  他说必须要准确是4加仑
- No, no, no, he said be precise. - Shit! - Exactly four gallons.
我跑了几里路后还要玩小孩游戏
Every cop in 15 miles is runnin' his ass off, and I'm out here playin' kids' games in the park!
你要集中精神在手上的问题?
Hey! You wanna focus on the problem at hand?
你说你知道  还叫我别开口
I thought you said you knew! You said don't say anything if you don't know!
把桶子给我  我们从头开始
I thought you said... Give me the fuckin' jug! We're starting over.
-不行  我们不能从头开始  -把水倒掉
- No, we can't start over. - Pour that out! - We can't start over.
-不行  不能从头开始  -把桶给我
- We're starting over! - We can't start over. - Give me the fucking jug!
把桶子放下来  你这笨王八
I'm gonna put my foot up your ass, you dumb mother...
-说啊  说出来啊!  -说什么
- Say it! Say it! - What?
你要叫我黑鬼  对吧?
You were gonna call me a "nigger," weren't you?
我没有
No, I wasn't.
你刚才有
Yes, you were!
否则你要叫我什么?
What were you gonna call me?
混球!  叫你混球  如何?
Asshole! How's that, asshole?
因我是白人所以你有心结  宙斯
You got some fuckin' problem with me because I'm white, Zeus?
是不是那样?  我对你有偏见吗?
Is that it, huh? Have I oppressed you?
我对你的同胞有偏见吗?
Have I oppressed your people somehow?
我告诉什么是你的问题
I'll tell you what your problem is, you don't like me 'cause...
你种族歧视
you're a racist!
什么
What?
你有种族歧视
You're a racist!
因我是白人所以你不喜欢我
You don't like me 'cause I'm white!
我不喜欢你是因你会害我送命
I don't like you because you're gonna get me killed!
剩下多少时间?
How much time?
糟糕  不到1分钟了
Oh, shit! We got less than a minute!
把那东西丢掉
Throw this thing away.
不行  会引爆炸弹
Look, we can't take it off of there. It'll detonate.
等下
Just wait. Wait a second, wait a second.
-我明白了  里面有2加仑  对吧  -对
- I got it, I got it! Exactly two gallons in here, right? - Right.
-剩下1加仑的空间  对吧  -是
- Leaving exactly one gallon of empty space, right? - Yeah.
-这里是5加仑整  对吧?  -没错
- A full five gallons here, right? - Right.
把5加仑倒1加仑出来
You pour one gallon out of the five gallons into there...
-就刚好剩4加仑  -4加仑
- we have exactly four gallons in there! - Four gallons!
-我们快点倒过去  -快
- Pour it in there! Come on! - Yes!
快点
Come on!
别洒出来
Don't spill! Don't spill it!
-行了  正好4加仑  -这下好了
- Good, good, good! Exactly four gallons! - All right!
你真聪明  麦克莱恩
You did it, McClane!
把它放到秤上去
Put it on the thing! Get it down there!
时间到了
Oh, shit!
解除
还来
Damn.
恭喜  你们还活着
Congratulations. You're still alive.
-说什么  -恭喜
- Huh? - Congratulations.
是的  我们解除了
Yeah, we did it.
再次令我讶异  约翰
You surprised me again, John.
这快变成我的嗜好了
This is becoming an ugly habit.
我没那种时间  赛门  听我说
Yeah, well, I don't have the time right now, Simon. Listen.
我们说好的  那炸弹在那里?
A deal's a deal. Where's the school bomb?
正好相反  时间还很充裕
On the contrary, you have lots of time.
你有
You have...
2小时47分钟
two hours and 47 minutes, precisely.
那些是测试你的智慧的时间
Plenty of time to test those wits of yours.
你个混蛋给我听着
Hey, listen, jerk-off! Let me tell you something!
我宿醉未醒  能不能省省?
I got a bad fuckin' hangover, all right?
我有点厌倦玩游戏了  炸弹在那?
And I'm a little sick of these fuckin' riddles! Now, where is the school bomb?
注意态度  约翰
Temper, John.
停战是有条件的
The road to truth has many turns.
喷水大象雕像下面有个信封
You will find an envelope under the rim of the fountain.
当你依上面建议的路线行走时
When you undertake the trip it suggests...
问你自己这个问题
ask yourself this question:
什么是42里的21?
What is 21 out of 42?
我们的进度已经落后了
We're behind.
我们应放弃其他的  离开这里
We should abandon the rest and go.
放轻松点  塔戈
Relax, Targo.
20条街之内没有任何警察
There's not a cop for 20 blocks.
让我们去扬基队的主场体育馆去  为什么
He's sending us to the home-team dugout at Yankee Stadium. Why?
我们是主场队  还有什么?
Well, we're the home team. We supposed to find something there?
什么是42里的21?
What's 21 out of 42?
-42的一半  还是21  -42什么呢?
- 21 again. Half of 42. - 42 what?
扬基队有多少球员?
How many players are on the Yankees ball club?
Twenty-five.
还有什么是21  21点?
What else is 21? Blackjack.
有个俱乐部
It's a club.
这是瞎猜一气
It's a wild-goose chase, is what it is.
最近的火车站在那?
Where is the nearest A train?
等下  也许会有小孩子拿走它
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. You know, some kid might find that.
你说的没错
You're right.
滚回来  你们两个小王八蛋
Come back here! You little sons of bitches!
-当心  -我记得你
- Hey, you! - Watch it. - I remember you!
要去哪儿?  你们在干什么?
Hey, hey, hey, where you going? Come here. What are you doing?
少管闲事  放开我  猪头
Don't! Let me go, dick-head!
说话小心点
Watch your mouth!
要为糖果去住少年感化院?
You want to go down to juvenile hall for a Butterfinger? Is that it?
看看周围  1个警察也没有
Look around, man. All the cops are into something.
像圣诞节一样  能偷掉市政厅
It's Christmas! You could steal City Hall!
-走  我们走  -我的自行车
- Come on. - My bike? - Let's go! Come on!
-那是我的自行车  -没错  圣诞节了
- Whoa, that's my bike! - Yeah, it's Christmas.
你要去那?
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Where you going?
-扬基体育馆不是这个方向  -我的自行车  你个混蛋
- Yankee Stadium's that way! - That's my bike, you asshole!
你们干嘛不碾过街上的每个人
Why don't you just run over everybody in the whole street?
麦克莱恩
McClane,
我们干嘛回到这里来?
what the fuck are we doing back down here?
让我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
华尔街没有什么?
What is it that Wall Street doesn't have?
怎么连你也开始玩猜谜游戏了?
What, is this stuff catching? You're talkin' in riddles!
别打岔  华尔街没有什么?
No, no, stay with me. What is it that Wall Street does not have?
没什么?
What?
没有学校
Schools.
华尔街有很多的是什么?
And what is it they have a shitload of?
是什么?
What?
纽约联邦储备银行
我马上回来
I'll be back in a minute.
这个怎么办?
What am I supposed to do with this?
交给那边的那几个人
Give it to those guys over there.
他在这了
He's here.
你必须说的更清楚点
Perhaps you could be a little more specific.
麦克莱恩在这了  他正走向银行
McClane is here. He's walking toward the bank.
那黑人则朝我而来
The black man is coming toward me.
那真可惜
Oh, now, that's a pity.
我叫他们去体育馆的
And after we'd gone to all that trouble at the stadium.
赛门  杀了他
Simon, kill him.
Stop toying with him,
不和他玩了
马上杀了他
and kill him now.
好了  就这样吧
Okay, so be it.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
艾林还有4个人在大厅
I'll inform Karl in the lobby.
你们收拾下离开那里
You pack up your team and get out of there.
这个呢?
And this one?
警察先生
Officer?
恐怕那件事上我需要答案
Yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm afraid I'm going to need an answer on that issue.
让他走
Let him go.
了解
Understood.
什么事?
Yes, sir?
约翰·麦克莱恩要我把这个给你们
John McClane says to give you this.
老天  别打开  是颗炸弹
Wait, wait. Jesus, don't open it. It's a bomb.
-另1个?  -正是
- Another? - Yeah.
我知道了  我们会料理的
Oh, I see. Um, oh, we'll take care of that.
我们必须走了
We'd better move now.
先生  非常感谢你
Sir, thank you so much for your assistance.
感谢之至
We really appreciate it. Thank you.
你在干什么?
我不要和它共乘同一辆车
小孩子可能
把它放在后面
你们就这样离开这了?
Hey! You, you, uh, leaving this place unguarded?
了解
你好吗?
How you doing?
还好
All right.
约翰·麦克莱恩  纽约警局
John McClane, NYPD.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事  今天是洗衣日
Yes. Laundry day.
有何效劳之处?  警官
What can I do for you, Lieutenant?
今天早上都那么安静吗?
Has it been quiet like this all morning here?
除了2小时前的爆炸之外
- Well, for... - Except for that big explosion a couple of hours ago.
在过去1小时没什么奇怪的事?
I mean, have you seen anything strange happen in the last hour or so?
没有
No.
而且这里还有警察
And we've had cops in here...
地铁出事后他们就一直在那
pretty steady since the subway thing.
我们正要去金库层巡逻
We were just gonna make a round on the vault floor...
假如你想一道来的话
if you want to tag along.
当然
Sure, yeah,
我要去
that's... Think I will.
你认为天气情况如何?
Yeah, what do you think of this heat this late in the year?
夏天到了
Yeah, Indian summer, huh?
好像待会要下倾盆大雨
Yeah, feels like it's gonna rain like dogs and cats later.
这是你们的人
Here's one of your guys.
奥托警官  对吧?
Detective, uh, Otto, isn't it?
-对  -约翰·麦克莱恩
- Yeah. - John McClane.
迈克  你好
Hey, Mike, how you doing?
有时我带他们1起下去运动下
I keep telling myself I'm gonna take the stairs just for the exercise...
他们不太喜欢这个
but on a hot day like this...
但似乎永远都有一长串的事要做
But it seems like I always end up riding the lift.
昨晚乐透中奖号码是多少?
Hey, what was the lottery number last night?
你们买彩票吗  不买?
Huh? You guys play the lottery? No?
我太太每周替我买2张乐透彩券
Yeah, my wife buys me two tickets every week, for the last ten years.
过去10年都买同样的号码
Plays the same two numbers all the time.
我问她为何不买别的号码?
I say, "Honey, why don't you play a different number?"
她说那是她的幸运号码
She goes, "Well, those are my lucky numbers."
彩券就在这
I got the tickets right here.
把枪放下!  现在就放下
Put that fucking gun down! Put the fucking gun down now!
放下
Put it down!
下面有人吗?
Hello! Anybody down here?
快点滚下来
Put your hands up! Put your fucking hands up now!
不  约翰  不
No! No! No, John, no! No!
约翰  是我  看到了吗
John, it's me! See?
老天  你差点让我心脏病发作
Jesus Christ, you almost gave me a heart attack.
你没事吧?
You all right? - Huh?
You all right?
那不是我的血
Yeah, yeah, it's not my blood.
这下面是怎么回事
What the hell's going on down here?
你四处去看看吧
Go take a look in there.
麦克莱恩  大伙都到那去了?
Hey, McClane, where the hell is everybody?
去他的赛门说
Simon fuckin' says!
我应该在数里外就看到他来了
I should've seen it coming a mile away.
这根本不是什么复仇的事
This was never about revenge.
而是抢劫
It's about a goddamn heist!
那些房间是装什么的?
But wh... what was in the room?
装这个
This.
这是什么?
What is this? Oh,
这是黄金?
shit! Is this gold?
是的
Yeah, it's gold.
这真的很重
Damn, this is heavy!
他们弄走1屋子的这个?
They cleaned out a whole room of this?
是的
Yeah.
那需要货柜或
You know, that would've taken, like, a-a-a-a tank...
或者是1辆
or a, or a, or a...
倾卸车
A dump truck.
14辆大倾卸车
Fourteen great big dump trucks.
我们差点被倾卸车撞到
We almost got hit by a dump truck.
错过了
Shit.
慢点儿
Damn! Slow down! Shit!
把那东西放下来
Put that shit down.
门都没有
No fucking way.
他们不会让你保有它的
They ain't gonna let you keep it.
等着瞧吧
Yeah, yeah, we'll see.
我们需要辆车
We're gonna need a car.
车?
A car?
你知道怎么接通点火吗?
You know how to hot-wire this thing?
我当然会  我是电气技师
Of course I can. I'm an electrician.
唯一的问题是
Only problem is...
花的时间太长
it takes too fucking long.
不在桥上
They're not on the bridge!
在下面  麦克莱恩  在罗斯福路上
Down there, McClane! The FDR!
我们走  快点
Let's go! Let's go! Come on!
糟了
Ah, shit!
怎么啦?
What?
他们把电话打坏了
They shot the phone.
太不幸了
Ah, too bad.
什么是42里的21?
Come on, what's 21 out of 42?
毫无头绪
I don't have a clue.
扬基体育馆呢?
Well, what about Yankee Stadium?
我们会去那里
We'll get there...
但不能让那个混蛋离开曼哈顿
but that son of a bitch is not getting off of Manhattan!
开快点
Move!
老天
Jesus Christ!
你以为自己是希拉里·克林顿夫人?
Who do you think you are, lady Hillary Clinton?
-有了  -有什么?  -希拉里·克林顿夫人
- That's it! - What? - Hillary Clinton!
42任总统
The 42nd president!
她会是第43任总统
No, she'd be the 43rd president.
行  但谁是第21任?
All right, all right, but who's the 21st?
我不知道
I don't know, l...
你不知道?
You don't know?
我不知道
No, I don't know.
你知道吗?
Do you know?
-我不知道  -那奇怪什么
- No! - Well...
这辆车的引擎太烂了  加速啊
What kind of engine's this piece of shit have? Come on. Step on it!
没有它那里也去不了  稍安勿燥
It's just a Yugo! It's built for economy not speed!
你干什么?
Whoa! What are you doing?
再找部电话
I'm going to get us another phone.
等下
Hey, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait!
谁是第21任总统?
Hey, who was the 21st president?
你去死
Go fuck yourself!
那个人火大了
That guy was pissed.
你的东西留在后座了
He'll feel better when he looks in the back seat.
背运  那是我的金条
Oh, shit! That was my gold bar!
我是麦克莱恩  接瓦尔特·考博警官
This is McClane. Get me Inspector Walter Cobb.
约翰  你在那里?
John, where the hell are you?
瓦尔特  不是复仇  是抢劫
Walter, it's not a revenge! It's a heist!
什么?
What?
联邦准备银行的金库有黄金
There's gold in the Federal Reserve...
他们搞走了一大堆
and they took a shitload of it!
他们驾倾卸车朝北走
They're headed north in dump trucks!
你喝酒了吗?  麦克莱恩
Have you been drinking, McClane?
自今天早上起就没喝了
No, not since this morning.
罗斯福路上有倾卸车队
Listen, there's a line of dump trucks northbound on the FDR at about 70th Street.
接近桥上  快派直升机到那去
You ought to close the bridge and then get some helicopters over there right away!
我现在什么都不能做
I couldn't close a hot dog stand right now!
所有人员都派出去了
I'm spread all over hell!
这个炸弹要怎么办?
What about this damn bomb?
查出来谁是第21任总统
Find out who the 21st president was.
和他有关系
It's got something to do with this!
约翰  第21任什么?
John? John, the 21st what?
瓦尔特
Walter! Shit!
什么烂电话
Goddamn cellular fuckin' phones!
去找门罗  叫他把59街北面
Get hold of Munsen in Triborough.
所有的桥梁都封闭掉
Tell him to close all the East River bridges north of 59th Street.
-让人都回来  -好的  -找倾卸车
- Get those people back! - Yeah. - Looking for dump trucks.
倾卸车?
Dump trucks?
麦克莱恩说
McClane says...
装满黄金的倾卸车在罗斯福路上
there are dump trucks headed up the FDR loaded with gold.
瓦尔特  罗斯福路禁行倾卸车
Walter, they don't allow dump trucks on the FDR!
去做
Connie!
行  你不要我争  我就不争
All right! You don't want I should argue...
不论是多愚蠢的事
I won't argue, no matter how stupid it is!
警犬队  到后面去查锅炉室
Canine, bring it around to the back, check out the boiler room.
找到什么了吗?  查理
Find anything, Charlie?
拿着X光机在这待1个星期
I could spend a week in here with an X-ray machine...
还是什么都找不到
and still not find it.
你没有1星期  查理  5分钟
You don't have a week, Charlie. You got five more minutes,
然后就要到86街去了
then we're moving up to 86th street.
我们已经尽快在这了
We're going as fast as we can.
什么事?
What's up?
麦克莱恩提到联邦准备银行大厦
McClane was mentioning something about the Federal Reserve building.
-那不就在华尔街爆炸案范围内?  -没错
- Isn't that right near that Wall Street bomb site we just left? - Yeah.
你要我们在这待多久?
How long do you want us to stay here?
在体育馆的人  撤还是留?
The men at the stadium, stay or go?
-卡尔现在应该报到了  -等会儿
- Karl should have checked in by now. - Moment.
接电话  快接
Come on, come on.
留在原处  麦克莱恩也许会出现
Stay where you are. McClane may still turn up.
放轻松  塔戈
Relax, Targo.
他就算还活着也不会和别人讲话
If he is still alive... he won't be talking to anyone.
下个出口
It's the next turn off.
自由发表  你在播出了  什么事
Hi, it's Elvis Duran, you're on the air. What's up?
首先我要告诉你节目有多精彩
First of all, I just want to tell you what a great show you've got.
我一直都在听你的节目
I listen to you all the time.
谢谢  你想聊点什么?
Thank you, thank you. What do you want to talk about?
你知道目前警察到处跑来跑去
Well, you know, all those cop cars screaming around everywhere?
晓得他们在干什么吗?
You know what they're up to?
在某学校有颗炸弹
There's a bomb in a school.
我表哥是警察
My cousin's a cop.
有人在某学校放了颗大炸弹
Somebody put a big bomb in a school somewhere.
只是他们不知是那所学校
- 705, 207... - Only they don't know which one...
-于是搜索每座学校  -别出声
- so they're searching all of them. - Shh, shh.
在纽约市的每所学校
Every school in the metropolitan area.
我的老天
Holy shit.
多瑞丝
Doris?
安妮
Annie?
多瑞丝  能连络上我太太吗?
Doris, can you get ahold of my wife?
特利  半个城市在打110
Turley! Half the goddamn city just called 911!
他们不见了
They've gone.
什么?
What?
他们不见了
They're gone!
这个人是谁  魔术师大卫?
Who is this guy, Houdini?
下面
Shit! Down there!
在那边
Down there!
这车有气囊吗?
This thing got air bags?
你那边有
Your side does.
我这边就不知道...
I don't know about mi...
麦克莱恩
McClane!
卡车里的人  让我看见你的手
In the truck, let me see the hands!
放在车门上
Put them on the door!
别杀我  别开枪
Don't kill me! Don't shoot me!
你是卡车司机?
You the truck driver?
不  我是美容家
No, I'm a beautician.
这不废话吗?  我当然是卡车司机
Of course, I'm a truck driver!
你要把这辆卡车开到那里去?
Where you taking this truck?
下水道
The aqueduct.
你把倾卸车开去下水道干什么?
What are you taking a dump truck to the racetrack for?
不  是饮用水下水道
No, the aqueduct! The a... Th-The water aqueduct!
下水道
Aqueduct?
看到吗?  由这直通凯斯密山
See? It goes from here all the way up to the Catskill Mountains.
什么东西?
What does?
那个  水管有60英里长
That! The water pipe. Goes for about 60 miles.
-你是工头?  -是我
- Hey, you the foreman? - Yeah.
纽约市警察
NYPD.
刚才有倾卸车通过吗?
You had any, like, extra dump trucks come through here in the last couple of minutes?
我要开罚单给它们  不听指挥
I'm gonna write those fucking clowns up! They better start paying attention to work orders...
-踢他们屁股  -你在说什么?
- or I'm gonna kick some butts! - Who-Who are you talking about?
有12辆冲进水道里去了
Ah, the dozen idiots who tore ass up the tube.
我们已经不再在那里装了
We're not loading up there anymore.
我们在这里装
We're loading over here!
怪不得不走桥  不怕直升机
So much for bridges and helicopters.
有地图显示隧道通到那吗?
You got a map showin' me where this tunnel goes?
就在这
Yeah, right here.
我们由锯木厂开始到考佛坝
We run pretty much up under the sawmill until you get up to the Coffer Dam.
由那里我们已经把水接通了
From there on, we've already brought the water down from the reservoir.
有任何方法能进出那里吗?
Any way to get in or out of there?
每隔2英里有个通风口
Yeah, there's a vent shaft every two miles.
我是指卡车
No, I mean with a truck.
到了考佛坝  卡车可以进出
At the Coffer Dam. You can get a truck in there.
沿着锯木厂公园路走
You can get there on the surface. Just follow the Sawmill River Park way up there.
大约20英里
It's about 20 miles.
我和你在那边见  行吗?
All right, I'm gonna meet you right there. All right?
等下  我要做什么?
Wait, wait! Wh-What am I supposed to do?
你要去扬基体育馆
You're going to go up to Yankee Stadium!
麦克莱恩
McClane!
快走  我们剩下不到2小时
Go! Get out of here! We got less than two hours!
算你狠
Goddamn it!
出什么事了?
Hey! Is somethin' wrong?
目前搞掉480码的岩块
480 yards of rock moved so far.
那是胡佛坝的10倍
Now that's ten times the Hoover Dam.
我们头顶上有516尺厚的岩块
Right now, there's 516 feet of rock above our heads.
这部份是3号隧道的第3阶段
This part is phase three of tunnel three.
自1954年开始设计
Planning for it began back in 1954...
建筑自1970年6月才开始
but construction didn't begin until June of 1970.
你知道3号通道最有趣的是什么吗?
You know what the most interesting part of tunnel three is?
是什么?  杰瑞
What's that, Jerry?
是通气口  每个通风口
The valves. Each one...
自1  2号隧道离开
a big departure from tunnels one and two.
别挡路啊!
Come on!
真是抛锚的好地方
What a hell of a place to break down.
等下  杰瑞
Hold it a minute, Jerry.
把你的安全帽给我
Let me have your hard hat.
有外套吗?  杰瑞
You got a jacket?
在这
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Here.
在这等会儿
Wait here a minute.
等他走到门旁的时候
Wait until he gets alongside the door.
各位  米奇·欧布莱恩  下水道安全官
Hey, fellas, Mickey O'Brien, aqueduct security.
我们接获报告说有人闯进来
Hey, listen, we had a report of a guy comin' through here with, uh, eight reindeer...
说是个快乐的胖老头
Yeah, they said he was a jolly, old fat guy...
留着雪白的胡子  穿着红格子衬衫
with a snowy white beard, cute, little red and white suit.
很讶异你们没看到他
I'm surprised you didn't see him.
这些家伙原来是用电话
What's with you guys and these phones?
应该还有别的东西
Maybe this'll give me something.
老天  那个人死了?
Holy shit! Is that guy dead?
杰瑞  我想他是死了
Yes, Jerry, I'm afraid he is.
老天
Jesus Christ.
我要你去找个叫考博的警官
I want you to get ahold of a guy named Cobb. Walter Cobb. C-o-b-b.
他是我的上司  叫他赶到这里来
He's the head of my police unit. Get him down here.
说是约翰·麦克莱恩叫你去的
Find him. Tell him you were with John McClane.
叫他查出谁是第21任总统?
Tell him to find out who the 21st president was.
切斯特·A·亚瑟
Chester A. Arthur.
什么?
What?
切斯特·A·亚瑟
Chester A. Arthur.
任期是1881年到1885年
1881-1885.
1880年被提名当选副总统
Nominated vice president in 1880.
你知道他是纽约海关关员吗?
Did you know he was Collector of Customs right here in New York?
我不知道  杰瑞  保重
No, I didn't know that, Jerry. Take care of yourself.
现在?
不  只有其中1个人
游戏结束
杀还是不杀
不杀
我们跟踪他
电视在播我们
TV's got us! TV's got us!
得先让这些交通队的人先走
We got to release these traffic guys!
不行  交通队能照顾自己
No! Traffic jams we can take care of later.
去查下这玩意有什么不对?
You find out what the hell is wrong with this thing!
频率拥塞
Frequencies are jammed!
瑞奇呢?
What about Ricky?
我不知道  我连络不到他
I don't know. I can't get ahold of him.
-但是  瓦尔特  联邦准备银行储存了  -嗯?
- But, Walter, Federal Reserve... - Yeah?
全世界的黄金储备
Biggest gold storage in the world.
派一组人到那去  找到瑞奇
You get a unit back down there. Find Ricky.
查出来出了什么事
Find out what the hell is going on.
瓦尔特
Walter!
-怎么  -你得听听他说
- Yeah? - You gotta hear this!
老天我以为是从后面进
Christ, I thought we were going in the back way.
这就是后面  瓦尔特
This is the back way, Walter.
8小时后全市的校园都会有暴动
In half an hour, you're going to have a riot at every school in this city!
切斯特·A·亚瑟国民学校
我们由顶楼开始  每层20人
We'll start at the top floor, put 20 men on each floor.
另外50人和我们到地下室去
Send the other 50 men down to the basement with us.
电话如何?
What about McClane?
什么都没
Not a word. I'm gettin' nothing.
占线的信号
Busy signals.
却斯特可能是最糟的
Westchester's probably worse than we are.
我们有点是孤注一掷  对吧?
This is kind of putting all our eggs in one basket, isn't it?
-我是说万一麦克莱恩错??  -瓦尔特  -又怎么了?
- I mean, what if McClane's wrong? - Walter! - Yeah?
马丁奈兹校长  考博警官
This is Principal Martinez. Principal Martinez, Inspector Cobb.
警官  你好
How do you do, Inspector?
你好  校长
How do you do, Principal Martinez?
我不想让你的孩子们紧张
I don't want to alarm your children. I wonder if you...
我要你把他们都带去礼堂
could move them all into the auditorium...
让他们保持冷静
and keep them calm.
我们接近水坝了  可以叫后卫了
We're coming to the dam. You can call the rear guard.
狄尔  你可以后撤了
Rear guard, you can close up now.
我们已通过了水坝  可以后撤了
We've reached the dam. You can come up now.
缪斯
Nils,
你可以后撤了
you can close in now.
缪斯
Nils!
注意  缪斯已经死了
Attention, attention, Nils is dead.
复诵  缪斯已死了  帕尔也死了
I repeat, Nils is dead, fuckhead. So is his pal.
还有自德国来的那4个人
And those four guys from the East German all-stars?
你留在银行的那些人会慢1点
Your boys down at the bank? They're gonna be a little late.
约翰
John.
你开的那卡车里
in the back of the truck you're driving...
有价值130亿美元的黄金
there's 13 billion dollars' worth in gold bullion.
不晓得能否做笔交易?
I wonder, would a deal be out of the question?
行  我也有个交易
Yeah, I got a deal for you.
趴在石头上让我碾
Crawl out from under that rock you're hidin' under, and I'll drive this truck up your ass.
那真是五颜六色
How colorful.
我告诉过你别和他玩耍
I told you not to toy with him!
谢谢  多亏你这么说
Thank you. That's very helpful.
你会危害整次行动和合约
You'll jeopardize the mission and the contract!
上船之前我们容易受伤害
We're vulnerable 'til we reach the ship!
我要把此事做个了结
I'm going to put an end to this.
住手
Stop!
塔戈  到这边来
Targo! Targo! Here! Come here!
我们把水坝炸掉
We blow the dam!
什么?
What?
我们淹死他
We drown him!
快  上去
瓦尔特
Walter!
看看这个
Take a look at this.
早上10点半送来的
The janitor said this one was delivered this morning about 10:30, right?
-没有接上线  -那又怎样?
- It's not hooked up. - Yeah?
再来看看前面
Okay. Now take a look at the front.
我们钻开铰链  叫大家出去
Okay, we drill the hinges. Get everybody out!
麦克莱恩
McClane!
你在那?
Where are you?
这边
Over here!
你真是有办法回到地面上来
You got a hell of a way of flagging somebody down!
你没事吧?
You all right?
你去过扬基体育馆了吗?
Did you go to Yankee Stadium?
去了  那里没有人
Yeah, there's nobody there!
你确定没有人?
You didn't see nobody?
是的
No!
没有人跟踪你?
Nobody was following you?
我告诉你  是他在恶整我们
I'm telling you, he's jerking us around!
要死了  麦克莱恩  快过来
Oh, shit, McClane! Come on, come on, come on!
看不见  什么人也没看到
No, no, I didn't see nobody.
还说没有人跟踪你
Nobody's following us! Let's go!
走!  走!  走!
Go! Go!
行了  拉开吧
It's not rigged. Pull it.
解除引爆密
我说你可以停止搜索了
Well, I'd say you could call off your search.
你能让它停下来吗?
Can you stop it?
我甚至不该碰它
I shouldn't even touch it.
谁晓得这玩意装了什么陷阱
Who knows what kind of booby traps this thing's got.
密码是什么
What about the code?
没有消息
No word.
我们何时疏散?
When do we evacuate?
赛门说有学童离开他就引爆
Simon says he sees one kid leave the building, boom!
当然有还在监视下的风险
Fine! There's a chance that somebody's still watching,
但我们不能坐以待毙啊!
but we can't stand here with our thumb up our ass, waiting for this freaking thing to blow up!
好
Okay.
倒霉
Shit! Shit!
头低点
Get your head down!
宙斯  开稳点
Come on, Zeus! Hold it steady! Hold it steady!
快!  快!
Go! Go!
别挡路
Outta the way!
超过去
Go around 'em! Go around 'em!
我查出来谁是第21任总统了
I found out who was the 21st president!
谁?
Who?
叫亚瑟的
Arthur.
切斯特·A·亚瑟?
Chester A. Arthur?
没错  切斯特·A·亚瑟
Chester A. Arthur, that's it, yeah.
切斯特·A·亚瑟国民学校?
Chester A. Arthur Elementary School?
没错
Yeah, that's it.
大家注意  我知道周5才会集合
Hi, kids. I know you usually have assembly on Fridays,
但今天是特别的日子
but today is special.
蓝柏先生是消防队的
Mr. Lambert here is from the fire department...
他要做一次全新的消防演习
and today he wants us to practice a brand-new fire drill.
所以我要你们分成两组
So, I want you to divide in half,
一组到那边
and I want half of you to go over here.
靠着墙排成1行
And line up against the wall.
另一组到那边去
The other half will go in this direction.
请安静快速的进行  好吗
Please do it very quietly and very quickly, all right?
大家站起来  老师请协助下
Everybody, up, please. Teachers, please help them.
消防演习个屁  他不是消防队的
Fire drill, my ass. That guy ain't from the fire department.
也许是收音机的那件事
Maybe it's because of the radio.
你是说他们在抓我们
You mean, like, they're after us? No.
汤尼对我们太坏了
Tony squealed on us.
不  他没有
No, he didn't.
走吧
Come on.
你去那?
Where you going?
我来开
Let me drive! Let me drive!
妈的
Goddamn it!
你以前为何不告诉我?
Why the hell didn't you tell me before?
他当然会炸掉那所学校
Of course he put the bomb up in that school!
他为何要那么做?
Why would he do that?
因为要吸引警方的注意力
Make sure he got your complete attention!
找保险丝盒
Find the fuse panel! Where...
什么?
What?
保险丝盒  保险丝盒在哪?
The fuse panel! Where's the fuse panel on this car?
就在这
It's right here. Right here.
把刹车防抱死(ABS)的保险丝拆下来
Pull out the Anti-Lock Brakes fuse!
我不知道哪个是刹车防抱死的
Shit! I don't know which one it is!
那就把它们全都拆掉
Well, then yank them all out then!
头低下去
Put your head down! Put your head fucking down!
情况会很糟
This is gonna be really bad.
听我说  抓稳了  行吗?
Listen to me. Hang the fuck on, all right?
发生了什么事?
Oh! Oh! What the fuck happened?
Triple-A: 提供路边救援协助服务的美国汽车俱乐部
你有3A卡吗?
You got a triple-A card?
-继续走  -借过
- Keep moving. - Excuse me.
继续走
Keep moving.
校工在最后一次检查所有建筑物
I've got the janitors making a last sweep of the building right now.
谢谢  马丁奈兹校长
Thank you, Ms. Martinez.
出来吧
Come on.
你一张  他一张
All right, five-card stud, threes and nines are wild.
保持低姿势
Stay down! Stay low!
你在干什么?
What the fuck are you doing?
审问他
Interrogating him.
他会告诉你什么?  我已经死了
Well, what's he gonna tell you? "I'm dead."
我不知道  所以我才会问他
Well, I ain't gonna know 'til I ask him, am I?
绕过去看杂物箱里面有没有阿斯匹灵
Go around and see if there's any aspirins in that glove box.
我不干  你去找
No way. You do it.
10个25美分  倾卸车那个人也有
Ten quarters. The guy in the dump truck had ten quarters.
正好10个25美分
Exactly ten quarters.
也许是要打长途电话
Well, maybe they were making long-distance phone calls.
不是
No.
是过桥费
It's for the bridge.
-什么  -是过桥费
- What? - It's for the toll on the bridge!
在那  在墙边  倾卸车  就在那
There! There! Down on the wharf! Dump trucks! Right there! Right there!
老天  他们已经装上船了
Christ! They got it loaded on the ship already!
海岸防卫队呢?
How about the Coast Guard?
要1小时才会到
It'd take 'em an hour to get here.
我们可以跳下去
We can jump!
什么?
What?
我们可以跳下去
We can jump!
你疯了  离甲板有1百尺
You're out of your fucking mind! It's 100 feet down to the deck!
但到吊杆没那么远
Yeah, but not to the crane it isn't.
钢缆会把你切成两8
The cables'd cut you in half.
我办得到
I can make it.
胡扯  下来
Bullshit. Get down. Get down.
看看车上有没有手套
Look in the back of that car for some gloves.
6个诱杀装置  4条死胡同
Six booby traps, four dead ends...
还有部份是真的通路
and a partridge in a pear tree.
好了  宝贝  我们开始吧
Okay, honey, let's dance.
我们有像比赛那样
We're gonna have sort of a race.
当我说跑的时候你们拚命向前跑
So, when I say go, I want you all to run like crazy.
跟着警察及消防队员
All of you, you follow the police officer and the firemen.
你们是我的领队
You guys are my front runners, okay?
瓦尔特  我想我们要动身了
Walter, think we're cutting this a little thin?
不  乔  我们等
No, Joe, we're gonna wait!
麦克莱恩还有可能得到密码
McClane still may get the code.
我要勾在那里?
Line me up with that crane.
勾在那边  就是那边
There! There! Right there! Right there!
就在那边  你的位置还可以
Right there, you're okay.
我看到它了
All right. I see it now, I see it.
这需要奇迹才行
Shit! This is gonna take a miracle!
把你的手指扣起来
Keep your fingers crossed. Okay, swing it.
稳住  你快勾到了  快了  差不多了
Okay, come on, come on, you almost got it. Almost, almost. Yeah, all right!
行了
Yeah, terrific!
你要去那?  急什么呢?
Where you going? Are you in a hurry?
这次我先下去  行吗?
I'm going first this time, all right?
新闻界来了  长官
We have the intercom rigged, sir.
瓦尔特  孩子们也许没问题
Walter, the kids may be fine, but you wait much longer...
再不出发我都要尿裤子了
and I'm gonna pee in my pants!
我们要等  康妮
We're gonna wait, Connie.
再等6分钟
Six more minutes.
麦克莱恩
Yo, McClane.
什么事
What?
看下面
Down there.
快  伙计  快
Oh, shit! Go, go, go, man! Go, go, go!
老天  谢谢你说服我别跳
Oh, boy! Am I glad you talked me out of jumping.
抬他的脚
Oh, fuck. Get his feet.
有些东西你们得看下
待会
很重要
不行  现在
这是在货柜里的东西
我们去找赛门  把他拖到电台那里
We go find Simon, drag him to the ship-to-shore radio...
逼问密码
and beat that fucking code out of him.
拿着这个
Here, take this.
它怎么发射?
How's it work?
你不会开枪?
You don't know how to shoot a gun?
我们黑人不是全都会用枪
Look, all brothers don't know how to shoot guns,
你这种族歧视的混球
you racist motherfucker.
去告我  把那往后拉再扣扳机
Sue me. Just yank back on that and pull the trigger.
如此而已
That's it.
就这样?
That's it?
就这样  别射到自己了
That's it. Just don't shoot yourself.
别逞英雄  找到他就来找我
Hey, don't be no hero. You find 'em, you come get me.
愚蠢
Stupid. Stupid!
设定好自动驾驶了?
You have the autopilot set?
好了  长官
Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
别动
Don't fuckin' move!
索马利亚人
Oh, the Samaritan.
把密码给我
Give me the goddamn code!
密码?
Code?
你是说为了学校那件事?
Oh! You mean for the school?
抱歉  我不能那么做
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
你现在就拨那个密码
You call in that code right now,
否则我把你这病鬼轰去另一个世界
or I blow your sick ass into the next world!
假如那是你得做的
If that's what you gotta do.
得先开保险
You gotta take the safety catch off.
老天
Oh! Goddamn!
那才能开枪
See? That works.
麦克莱恩在那?
Now, where's McClane?
你说什么?
What was that?
他说别开枪
He said, "Don't shoot."
好  查理  我们要疏散了
Okay, Charlie, we're gonna have to go with the evacuation.
我们动身
We're gonna go!
你们听到他说的了
Well, you heard the man! Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
我们动身
We're gonna go! Let's move it! Come on!
听我的口令
On my mark!
5  4  3  2  1  动身
Five, four, three, two, one, go!
走!  走!  走!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
我们动身吧!  大伙们走!
Let's do it! Okay, gang, let's go!
跑!  跑!  跑!  大家跑快点!
Go. Go, go! Hip-hop! Hip-hop! Come on, everybody! Let's go!
他们在干嘛?
What are they doing?
-你们要去那?  -等等我们
- Yo! Where you goin'? - Hey, wait for us! -
你们要去那?
Hey, where you goin'?
我每次都以为杀死你了
I see you all dead, little man, policeman...
但你总是阴魂不散
and you don't go away.
我不是那么3易放弃的  朋友
Yeah, I'm that fucking Energizer bunny.
你现在要去那?
Where are you going now, huh?
要逮捕我吗?  小兔子
Going to arrest me, bunny?
不是
No.
我不是想逮捕你
I don't think I'm gonna arrest you.
我要弄死你
I'm gonna break you.
我早知道是胡扯  没人在监视
I knew it was bullshit. There's nobody watching.
该把查理叫出来了
Time to get Charlie out.
走了  查尔斯  时间到了
Let's move, Charles. Time's up.
再给我30秒
Give me another 30 seconds.
就算是孩子也要1分15秒  查理
It takes a minute-fifteen if you're a kid, Charlie...
而且你体重不算轻  快走
and, last I looked, you weren't too light on your feet. Now move!
上面这里  救救我们
Up here! Help us!
我的天
Oh, my God!
-我们在这里  -看这里
- We're here! Come on! - Look over here!
把他们弄出来
Christ! Get 'em out of there!
门锁着的
The rooms are locked. The rooms are locked!
走  乔
Come on, Joe!
让下
Out of the way!
上面写4号的钥匙
Any one marked four!
怎么回事?  瓦尔特
What's going on, Walter?
楼里还有孩子
We still have kids in the building.
我留下来继续
I'm staying.
不  查理  离开那里
No, Charlie! Get out of there!
你看过亚历山大那个节目吗?
You ever see that show called The Addams Family?
你知道在节目上做什么比赛吗?
They got a motherfucker on there called "Lurch"!
我想我要让你尝尝滋味
You don't think I'm gonna let you get to that gun, do you?
去你的
Fuck!
-救命  救救我们  -4号钥匙
- Help! Help! Help us! - Four! Four!
-让我来  -去它的  离开门
- Let me put it in! - Fuck it! Get out of the way!
他们在那?  瓦尔特
Where are they, Walter?
还在里面
Still in.
没有胆子  没有荣耀
No guts, no glory.
如果能到屋顶上  我们可以跳到隔壁楼去
If we get to the roof, we can jump to the next building!
让开
Out of the way!
-快!  -救我们
- Okay, come on. - Help us!
到上面来  快!
Get 'em up here! Get 'em up here! Come on! Come on!
紧急求救!  呼叫海岸防卫队
Mayday! Mayday, Bridgeport Coast Guard. Bridgeport Coast Guard, come in!
快  孩子们
- Come on, kids! - Go, kids!
-太宽了  -来  蹲下
- Shit! It's too far! - Over here! Down!
没有胆子  没有荣耀
No guts, no glory.
他们停在港口的中央
It's a big, fucking white fucking boat in the middle of the harbor!
请别挂断
Please stay on the line.
当然不会挂断
Yeah, sure, I'll stay on the line.
红糖水?
Pancake syrup?
笨蛋!  混蛋!
Stupid! Stupid! Asshole!
哈啰  约翰·麦克莱恩
Hello, John McClane.
不是真的有学校炸弹  对吧?
There was never any bomb in the school, was there?
当然没有  我是军人不是怪物
Of course not. I'm a soldier not a monster.
虽然有时候我为怪物工作
Even though I sometimes work for monsters.
真的炸弹在这艘船上
No, the real bomb is on this ship.
海岸防卫队
The Coast Guard.
我告诉他们船在那里
I was tellin' 'em where the boat was.
游戏结束了
Game over, huh?
不尽然
Not quite over.
海岸防卫队  请回答
Bridgeport Coast Guard, come in, please.
他们把你保留在线上?
They put you on hold?
他们要我等
She told me to stay on the line.
天啊!  我真喜爱这个国家
Oh, God, I love this country.
你知道你弟弟是个混球吗?
You know, your brother was an asshole.
他真的是
Yeah, he really was an asshole.
他是吗?  他真的是
He was? He was an asshole.
你说对了
You, you got his number. Huh?
知道了
Yeah, okay.
原谅我  请把麦克莱拖到下面去
Forgive me. Would you help Mr. McClane below?
-痛  痛  -小心点
- Ow. Ow. - Careful now.
你已经连络了
Now, do you have the communique?
海岸防卫队  请回答
Bridgeport Radio, come in, please. Bridgeport...
海岸防卫队
Coast Guard.
你接了  亲爱的
Are you there, dear?
是的
Yes, we're here.
你是否能记录一项讯息
Do you have the ability to record a message?
行
Yes.
他现在说话了
Then please begin now.
好
All right.
这是CRF的宣言
This is a communique from the CRF.
长久以来西方窃取世界的财富
For too long... the West has conspired to steal the wealth of the world...
置人道主义于不顾  制造经济恐慌
consigning the balance of humanity to economic starvation.
今天我们要让大家有同等立足点
Today, we will level the playing field.
几分钟后联邦储备银行的黄金
In a few minutes, the contents of the Federal Reserve Bank...
你们经济的立足点
the gold your economies are built on...
会在爆炸后
will be redistributed by explosive...
粉碎于长岛边的海底
across the bottom of the Long Island Sound.
假如你们有幸  竭诚欢迎观赏
If you are not in gridlock, I invite you to come and watch.
你要把它们全炸掉?
You're gonna blow it all up?
正是那个意思
That's the idea.
中东某位先生
There are some gentlemen in the Middle East...
认为能从中获暴利
who seem to think that they'll make a great deal of money.
去看着大家安全的离开
See the men safely off the ship,
我们在船舷边见面
and I'll see you in the port-side launch.
那为何要杀麦克莱恩
What the hell's all this got to do with killing McClane?
那是人生的红利
Life has its little bonuses.
你不是说你不喜欢你弟弟?
Didn't I hear you say, you didn't even like your brother?
不喜欢他是一回事
There's a difference, you know, between not liking one's brother...
但被个笨爱尔兰人扔出窗户不同
and not caring when some dumb Irish flatfoot drops him out of a window.
我甚至不认识那个王八蛋
Hey, I didn't even know that motherfucker!
我也没有邀请你们上船
Yes, but I never invited you aboard this ship.
有什么方法能停止这玩意吗?
No riddle's gonna stop this motherfucker?
没有密码  没有哑谜
No code, no riddle...
没有倒数计时
no fancy little countdown.
猪头
Hey, fuckhead.
对  就是你  猪头
Yeah, you, fuckhead.
有件事我必须知道
There's just one thing I gotta know.
有阿斯匹灵吗?
You got any aspirins?
我头痛了整天
I've had a bad fucking headache all day long.
今天是你的幸运日
Must be your lucky day.
整瓶留着吧
Keep the bottle.
锁上
Lock.
黄金在那?
Where is the gold?
他背叛了我们  货柜里全是这个
He's betrayed us. The containers are filled with that!
我若没有救你就不会在这了
If I hadn't have saved your fucking ass, I wouldn't be sittin' here with you...
还有炸弹及价值1000亿美金的黄金
about to blow up with a hundred billion dollars in fucking gold!
有坏消息  你不会和我1起炸掉
Hey, well, I got some bad news. You're only gonna blow up with me.
什么?
What?
船上没有黄金
There's no gold on this boat.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
我知道那个人我知道他的家庭
'Cause I know the man, I know the family.
比炸掉1000亿黄金更好的方法
The only thing better than blowin' up a hundred billion dollars' worth of gold...
是让别人认为他那么做了
is making people think you did.
那么它会在那?
Yeah? Well, where is it?
应该是在码头调了包
I don't know. He must've switched it back on the docks somewhere.
那应该要让你觉得好过点吗?
Oh, yeah, that's supposed to make me feel better?
不是
No.
你对别的事也错了  你不会死
You're wrong about the other thing, though. You're not gonna die.
你晓得某种警察技俩能松开手铐
Yeah? You know some cop trick about handcuffs that's gonna get us out of this?
是的  有把钥匙
Yeah, use a key.
你会开这种锁吗?
You know how to pick this lock?
这又是黑人的事吗?
Is this some Black shit again?
别来那套种族问题的争论
Now will you stop with that racial shit?
你到底会不会开锁?
Are you a fucking locksmith or not?
会  假如我有工具的话
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I could do it if I had something to do it with.
我有一节电线
How about a splinter of that cable I slid down?
那也许可以
That might work.
-坚持下  -你在干什么?
- Hold on. - What the fuck are you doin'?
妈的
Oh, fuck! Shit! How's that?
这个行不行?
Is that big enough?
也许有用
Shit, yeah. Yeah, that might work.
我吐到你的手上  把手伸过来
All right, I'm gonna drop it in your hands. Cup your hand.
别把它丢掉了  行吗?
Don't drop this motherfucker, all right?
吐好一点
Get it. Get it right. Come on.
-准备好了吗?  -1...
- You ready? - One...
-预备  -2  吐
- Ready? - Two, spit it.
-成功  -拿到了吗?
- Yeah! - Get it?
快  把你的手移开
Come on, come on. Move your hands.
麦克莱恩  我开始喜欢你了
Okay, okay. Damn, McClane, I was just startin' to like you.
别喜欢我  我是个混球
Yeah? Well, don't. I'm an asshole.
你在说什么?
What are you talkin' about now?
我对你说谎  宙斯
I lied to you, Zeus.
关于什么?
About what?
记得我告诉你炸弹在哈林区找到
You remember I said Weiss found that bomb up in Harlem?
-记得  -他们是在唐人街找到的
- Yeah. - They found it down in Chinatown.
那是太低级了  连你都不肯那样
Oh! Oh, now, that's low! Even for a white motherfucker like you, that's low.
所以我说我是混球
I told you I was an asshole.
那是什么?
What the fuck was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是我唯1能让你跟我走的方法
Look, it was the only way I could get you to come with me.
你有老婆吗?  麦克莱恩
Uh-huh. You got a wife, McClane?
有
Yeah.
我奇怪竟然有人会跟你在一起那么久  久到结婚
I'm surprised anybody could stay with you long enough to be married.
她没有跟我在一起太久  算是分居
Yeah, well, she didn't stick around too long. We're sort of separated.
什么叫算是分居?
What the fuck is "sort of separated"?
她当时在洛杉矶  我在纽约
Well, she was in L.A., I was in New York.
我们在电话上吵架  她挂断电话
Had a fight on the phone, she hung up.
我没有再打过去
I didn't call her back.
那是多久之前
How long ago was that?
大约是1年前了
About a year ago now.
你在笑什么?
What the fuck are you laughing about?
你真疯了?  笨到不会拿起电话来
You threw away your marriage because you were too fucking stupid to pick up the phone?
你认为那很好笑?  笑别人的痛苦
What? You think that's funny, huh? You laugh at other people's misfortunes?
你1切都怪罪你太太  对吧?
I bet you blame that shit on your wife too, right?
我太太是个很固执的女人  是的
Well, my wife is a very stubborn woman. Yes.
别笑了  快点解开手铐
Man, you better stop fucking laughing and undo these cuffs!
马上就解开  解开了  这样如何?
I'm almost there! There. How's that for concentration?
-糟了  -怎么啦?
- Oh, shit! - What?
我把那玩意儿给弄掉了
Fuck! I dropped the thing!
-你把那破玩意儿掉哪了?  -破东西
- You dropped the fucking thing? - Goddamn it!
东西掉到那里去了?
Shit! Where is it! Where'd it go?
快找到它
Just find it, find it, all right?
我什么都没看见
I don't fucking see it!
那是什么?
What the fuck is that?
我想我让它生气了
I think I made it mad.
快走  麦克莱恩  快离开这
Go, McClane! Get the fuck out of here!
我必须想个办法
Fucking do something!
麦克莱恩  听我说
Goddamn it, McClane! Listen to me!
走
Just go.
我们待在一起1天了都没事
I have a hard enough time getting through the day without having your death on my conscience, man.
我不想良心上愧疚  闭嘴快设法
Shut the fuck up, and think! All right?
好了  工具  轮机室有工具
Okay, okay. Tools, tools. Check the engine room.
没时间了
There's no time!
它现在在干嘛?
What the hell's it doing now?
在混合
It's mixing.
这回死了
Shit!
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
预备好  往前倾
Get ready. Lean forward.
什么?
What?
往前倾
Lean forward, goddamn it!
-干什么  -往前倾  -你他妈干什么?
- What? - Lean forward! - What the fuck are you doing?
现在要爆炸  往前倾
All right, it's gonna go fast! Lean forward!
不!  不!  不!
What? No, no, no, no!
往前倾
Lean forward!
准备好  挪开你的手
Get ready! Move your hands!
这回死定了
Damn! Motherfuckin' shit! Shit!
快跑
Come on! Come on!
我的腿
Oh, fuck! My leg!
快走  上楼
Come on! Get upstairs! Come on! Go, go, go, go,
跑!  跳上去
go! Jump stairs!
往哪边走
Oh, shit! Oh, damn it! Which way?
从这里下到船尾部
Let's go! Let's go! Down here to the back of the boat! Come on!
我们不能停  快
Goddamn it! Oh! Run, goddamn it!
-在跑  -对  加油
- I am! - Yeah, come on!
-行吗?  -行  -当心
- You all right? - Yeah. - Watch! Watch! Watch! Watch!
走!  跳下去
Let's go! Down here in the back!
他的情况如何?
How's he doin'?
我腿部中枪  你认为呢?
I got shot in the leg. How you think I'm doin'?
他不会有事的
He's gonna be just fine.
你呢?
How about you?
没事  把瑞奇抬出来了吗?
Fine. Did you get Ricky out of there?
他们找到他了
Yeah, they found him.
你不会有事吧?
Are you gonna be all right?
我头痛的要命  他们生我气吗?
Got a bad headache. Think they're mad at me?
我不会去担心他们
I wouldn't worry about them.
最后他们会去找你
They'll get to you eventually,
但现在他们忙着打捞作业
but right now they're busy with this salvage operation, I guess.
不  是卓吉斯
No! Dr-Dredges! Dredges!
他们在浪费时间  下面没有黄金
They're just wasting their time. There's no gold down there.
此话怎讲?
What do you mean?
他带走了  他打败我了
He took it with him. He beat me.
约翰  他打败了我们每1个人
John, he beat all of us.
他不是针对你来的
He wasn't playing against you.
去你的  麦克莱恩  你还活着吧?
Fuck that, McClane! You're still alive, aren't you?
-对吧?  -是
- Well, aren't you? - Yeah.
那我们输了?
So we lost.
蓝柏  给他25美分
Lambert, would you give him a quarter?
混球
Asshole.
是约翰打的对方付费电话
Yeah, it's collect from John.
卡门  告诉她  她会付费的
Yeah, uh, Carmen, just tell them you'll accept the charges.
那王八蛋真的有阿斯匹灵
The son of a bitch had aspirin.
我是约翰  我还好
Yeah, it's John. Yeah, I'm hangin' in there.
荷莉在吗  好我等着
Is Holly there? Yeah, I'll hold on.
宙斯  等下
Zeus! Hold up! Whoa!
约翰  混蛋  你个...
John? John? Goddamn it, you son of a...
北方边界
昨天
Yesterday...
昨天我们是支没有国家的军队
Yesterday we were an army with no country.
明天我们得决定买那个国家
Tomorrow we have to decide which country we want to buy!
记住  这一切都是因为
And remember this is all due to...
容易受骗上当的纽约警察局
the g-g-g-g-g-g-gullibility of the New York Police Department!
警察局
Police Department!
敬死去的同志
副官  你接手
Lieutenant. Take over.
好了  大家听着
All right, listen up!
第一队8小时后搭校车出发
First squad, you muster out in half an hour in the school bus!
飞机在诺瓦·史考提亚
我们能在10分钟内离开
不用急
No rush.
范·洛根
Herr Jurgen,
你当神父
you'll be the padre!
灯  把灯灭了
Lights! Douse those lights!
北方边界
猪头
Hey, dick-head!
我来的不是时候吗?
Did I come at a bad time?
我想她生你的气了  麦克莱恩
Whoa! I think she's pissed at you, McClane!
-拿子弹  子弹  -快
- Bullets! Bullets! - Go!
他在我们正下方  转回来
He's under us right now. Come on back around. Come on back around.
没错  快逃命吧!
That's right! Run, motherfuckers!
宙斯  会由你那边出现
Zeus, what do you got out of your side?
就象蟑螂看到光就都出来了
Look like roaches with the lights comin' on.
要去诺瓦史考提亚吗?
Are we going to Nova Scotia?
你和卡车一起走
You go with the trucks.
我有点私事要解决
I have something personal to finish.
我们开工吧
Let's go to work!
没错  逃命吧  把你们了结掉
That's right! Run, motherfuckers! The exterminators are here!
搞什么?
What the fuck? Oh, shit! Fuck it!
后面有东西
There's smoke back here! What the hell's going on here?
后面有麻烦
We got a chopper behind us!
有枪吗?
You got a gun on board?
这是什么?  麦克莱恩
What is this? Jesus, McClane!
他在我们后面
I'm gonna try and get the fuckin' chopper!
稳住  我什么都看不见
I can't see a goddamn thing! Hold still.
-麻烦了  -麻烦是什么意思?  -失去控制了
- I've lost my... - What do you mean, "Oh, shit"? - I've lost it!
抓稳了  我们要下去了
All right, hang on, hang on! We're going down!
看到电线了吗?  电线
See this high tension wire? See this wire?
麦克莱恩  搞什么鬼?
Hey, McClane! What the fuck...
有烟  到处都是烟在熏我
Hey, we got smoke! We got fuckin' smoke and shit flyin' on me here!
卡车!  卡车!
Truck! Truck!
稳住  我们下降了
Hold on. Here we go.
走  我们必须离开这
Come on! We gotta get outta here!
他随时会对我们开枪
He's gonna start shootin' at us any second!
我们离开这
Get him outta here!
安全带卡住了  我解不开
The belt's stuck! I can't get it off!
小心!  他来了
Look out! Here he comes!
我弄不开  麦克莱恩
I can't get out, McClane!
把他弄走
Get him outta here.
你要去那?
Where you goin'?
我试着吸引他的注意
I'm gonna try and get his attention.
无法更好了
Shit! Just keeps gettin' better and better.
我想像不到加拿大会这么好玩
I had no idea Canada could be this much fun.
给我个可以射击的目标
Just give me something to shoot at. Come on, hotshot.
把脸露出来
Show me that smilin' face.
向你弟弟问好
Say hello to your brother.
快离开这
Get outta here!
再见  王八蛋
Yippie-ki-yay, motherfucker.
看起来你吸引到了他的注意力
Looks like you got his attention.
没错
Yeah, looks like it.
我们该叫消防车
Think we should call a fire truck?
去他的  让他烧吧
Ah, fuck him. Let him cook.
糟了
Oh, shit!
怎么啦?
What?
我之前让荷莉在电话上等着
I left Holly hangin' on hold.
再打给她
Aw, call her back.
她会发火的
I don't know. She's gonna be pissed.
会过去的
She'll get over it.
我不知道  宙斯
I don't know, Zeus.
如同我所说的  她很固执
Like I said, she's a very stubborn woman.
可是她凑巧嫁给你
Yeah, she'd have to be to stay married to you.